我的世界在过去五年间经历了巨大变革
Minecraft has changed a lot in the last 5 years.
翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
♥无偿翻译，用爱发电♥
本视频将带您回顾近五年所有版本更新中新增内容的演变历程
So in this video, I'll be showing you the evolution of all the
使用AI工具翻译，如有不准确的地方请在弹幕或评论区指正，谢谢！
！！真的有人看不到这行字！！
things added to Minecraft's updates in the last 5 years.
我们将从2020年发布的1.16下界更新开始讲述
We'll be starting with the 1.16 Nether update which was released in 2020.
翻译质量权威评价：原来25年就有小拉即用机翻糊弄人了
别忘了在评论区告诉我你最喜欢的版本更新
Be sure to tell me your favourite Minecraft update in the comments below.
现在 让我们开始吧！
Anyways, here we go!
今天为大家盘点1.16版本新增的100项内容
Today I bring you 100 things that were added in Minecraft 1.16.
1.16下界更新的首个新特性是下界合金工具套装
The first feature added in the Minecraft 1.16 Nether update
is the addition of the new tools known as netherite tools.
没错 这个版本新增了下界合金镐
That's right, 1.16 has added a netherite pickaxe,
剑 锹 斧和锄 它们的外观如图所示
sword, shovel, axe and hoe and they all look like this.
这些下界合金工具不仅威力更强 耐久度也超越钻石工具 成为游戏中最顶级的存在
These netherite tools are more powerful and have more durability than
diamond tools making them the best tools in the game.
哦对了 这些下界合金工具能在岩浆中漂浮且不会被烧毁
Oh, and these netherite tools can float in lava and cannot burn so yeah,
它们确实非常出色
they're really good.
1.16版本还新增了如图所示的下界合金盔甲
Next up in 1.16 is the addition of netherite armour which looks like this.
与工具一样 下界合金盔甲比钻石盔甲更坚固耐用 且在岩浆中不会燃烧
Just like the tools, the netherite armour is stronger and
more durable than diamond armour and doesn't burn in lava
成为游戏中最强大的护甲装备
either making it the best armour in the game.
需要注意的是 即使穿着这套盔甲 你仍会受到岩浆伤害
Just note that you still take damage from lava when wearing this armour so yeah,
你并非完全免疫伤害 所以还是要小心行事
you're not fully protected so be careful.
下界在我的世界1.16版本中迎来全面革新 新增了四大生物群系 它们分别是以下这些
The nether has been overhauled in Minecraft 1.16
with the addition of four new biomes and those biomes are the following.
首个新增的生物群系是灵魂沙峡谷 它长这样
The first biome added is the soul sand valley which looks like this.
这个群系由裸露的下界化石构成
This biome is composed of uncovered nether fossils,
遍布灵魂沙 弥漫着诡异的蓝色雾气 还有这种名为灵魂火的新型蓝色火焰
soul sand, this creepy blue fog and this new blue fire known as soul fire.
接下来是玄武岩三角洲生物群系
Next up we have a biome that is called basalt deltas.
这个群系呈现如此地貌 被描述为下界新增的火山地带
Now the biome looks like this and is described as a volcanic
biome added in the nether consisting of pillars of basalt
由玄武岩柱和成片的新型黑石方块构成 黑石方块长这样
and large areas of the new blackstone blocks which look like this.
绝对是个充满神秘与阴森气息的群系
Definitely a very mysterious and creepy biome.
1.16版本第三个新增群系是绯红森林 景观如下
The third biome added in 1.16 is the crimson forest which looks like this.
如你所见 绯红森林就是片森林 遍布着新型绯红菌柄树
As you can see the crimson forest is a well a forest
and it's filled with these new crimson fungi trees which you can
从中可获得新型木板及其他木质建材
obtain a new type of wooden plank from and other wood related blocks.
绯红森林还新增了菌光体方块  其发光效果类似萤石以及两种新型生物
The crimson forest also features the new shroom light block
which emits light similar to glowstone as well as two new mobs
我稍后会详细介绍
which I will talk about shortly.
下界更新的最后一个生物群系是诡异森林
The final biome we have in the nether update is the warped forest.
诡异森林景观如下  作为绯红森林的蓝色变种这里生长着扭曲菌柄树
Now the warped forest looks like this and is a blue
variation of the crimson forest featuring warped fungi trees which
同样可以从中获取专属的木质板材
again you can obtain its own wooden planks.
诡异森林还栖息着下界更新加入的另一种新生物  话不多说 我们这就来介绍
The warped forest also features another new mob
added in the nether update so without further ado let's talk about the
四种全新生物
four new mobs.
1.16下界更新带来的首个生物是猪灵  它们长这样
The first mob we've been blessed with in the 1.16
nether update is the piglin and it looks like this.
猪灵是一种敌对生物  生成时会携带金剑或弩  它们可在我先前提到的绯红森林或下界荒地中生成
The piglin is a hostile mob that spawns with either a gold sword
or a crossbow and they can spawn in either the crimson forest biome I mentioned earlier,
在新型堡垒遗迹结构或是常规的下界生物群系中生成
the new bastion remnant structure or the regular nether biome.
猪灵痴迷黄金  只要你穿戴至少一件金质护甲  它们就不会主动攻击
Piglins love gold, so much that they will not attack you
if you are wearing at least one piece of gold armour.
随着猪灵的加入
With the addition of piglins,
游戏新增了以物易物机制  玩家可用金锭与猪灵交易
a new trading mechanic known as bartering has been added
to the game which allows the player to trade gold ingot for
换取各式各样的物品
various different items.
只需将金锭扔到猪灵面前  它们会检查几秒钟  然后给你回礼
Just simply throw a gold ingot in front of a piglin
and watch them inspect it for a few seconds resulting in you getting
屏幕上显示的这些物品之一
one of the following items you see on screen.
1.16版本新增的下一个生物是疣猪兽  它们长这样
The next mob added in 1.16 is the hoglin which looks like this.
疣猪兽生成于绯红森林生物群系  对玩家具有攻击性  务必小心应对
And now the hoglin spawns in the crimson forest biome
and is also a hostile mob to the player so be very careful.
尽管疣猪兽是极其凶猛的生物
Despite hoglins being very scary mobs,
它们也得提防着点  因为猪灵会主动猎杀疣猪兽
they have to be careful as piglins will actively hunt down hoglins,
它们会主动攻击疣猪兽  并在猎杀成功后跳起胜利之舞
attack them and do a little victory dance after killing them.
可怜的疣猪兽啊
That poor hoglin man,
猪灵真是太残忍了
the piglins are so mean.
1.16版本引入的第三种生物  是疣猪兽的僵尸变种  名为
The third mob introduced in Minecraft 1.16 is the zombified variant of the hoglin which is called,
僵尸疣猪兽  它们长这样
well, the zoglin and they look like this.
僵尸疣猪兽只会在疣猪兽进入主世界至少15秒后转化生成
Now a zoglin will only spawn if a hoglin enters the overworld for
at least 15 seconds where they will then proceed to
颤抖着变异成僵尸疣猪兽
shiver and turn into a zoglin.
顺带一提  僵尸疣猪兽同样具有攻击性  且不会在阳光下自燃  千万要当心
Oh and it goes without saying that zoglins are also hostile
and they cannot burn in sunlight so be careful.
下界更新引入的最后一种新生物  是名为炽足兽的物种  它们长这样
The last and final mob introduced in the nether update is
a new mob called the strider and they look like this.
炽足兽是一种被动生物生成于下界的熔岩海上  当它们离开熔岩时会开始
The strider is a passive mob that spawns on lava oceans in
the nether and when they leave the lava they will begin to
颤抖着变成蓝紫色
shiver and turn a bluish purple colour.
真为它们感到难过啊
I feel so bad for them man,
看看它们的样子
just look at them.
炽足兽还能作为穿越熔岩的交通工具
Striders also provide a way to travel across lava.
如果你给炽足兽装上鞍  同时手持新增的诡异菌钓竿  就能控制它的行进方向
So if you put a saddle on a strider while holding the newly added
warped fungus on a stick then you can control where
这意味着你可以穿越广阔的熔岩海  简直太棒了
the strider moves meaning you can get across massive lava oceans which I think is awesome.
下界更新新增的另一个特色  是名为堡垒遗迹的全新结构
The next feature added in the nether update is the addition of
a new structure which is called a bastion remnant.
堡垒遗迹是庞大的城堡状建筑  外观如图所示  它们会生成在下界所有生物群系中
So bastion remnants are large castle like structures
that look like this and they are found in all biomes of the nether
除玄武岩三角洲外的所有生物群系
except basalt deltas.
堡垒遗迹是猪灵族群的聚居地  若结构中生成疣猪兽马厩  也可能出现疣猪兽
Bastion remnants are home to piglin mobs
but hoglins may also spawn if hoglins stables generate within the structure.
在堡垒遗迹的藏宝室里  你能找到各类战利品从钻石到新增的
In the bastion remnant you can find treasure rooms allowing you to
obtain all sorts of loot ranging from diamonds to the
名为“猪步”的音乐唱片
newly added music disc which is called pigstep.
这张新唱片超棒  而堡垒遗迹是唯一获取地点  记得仔细搜寻
This new music disc sounds awesome and a bastion remnant is
the only place you can find it so keep a look out.
遗迹中还会生成岩浆怪刷怪笼  同样需要留意
You can also find magma cube spawners in bastion remnants as well so look out for those too.
1.16版本还新增了  名为远古残骸的全新矿石  外观如图所示
Next up in 1.16 is the addition of a brand new ore which is called ancient debris and it looks like this.
这种稀有矿石仅生成于  下界底层区域  必须使用钻石或
Now ancient debris is a rare ore found in the bottom layers of the nether and can only be mined with a diamond or
下界合金镐才能开采
netherite pickaxe.
获得远古残骸后  放入熔炉冶炼可得名为下界合金碎片的新物品
When you obtain ancient debris you can smelt it in a furnace
to obtain a new item called netherite scrap and it looks like this.
将下界合金碎片与金锭  在工作台中合成  即可制成下界合金锭
With the netherite scrap you can combine it with gold ingot in a
crafting table to create a netherite ingot.
随后将下界合金锭与钻石镐于锻造台中合成 即可将镐升级为
You can then combine a netherite ingot with a diamond pickaxe in a smithing
table to upgrade that pickaxe into the new
我之前提到的下界合金镐
netherite pickaxe I mentioned earlier.
装备升级同理
The same also applies with armor.
将下界合金锭与钻石装备结合  即可升级为下界合金装备
Combine a netherite ingot with diamond armor and you get netherite armor.
下界更新还新增了  名为废弃传送门的结构
Another structure that's been added in the nether update is the addition
of ruined portals which look like this.
废弃传送门是自然生成的  下界传送门结构同时存在于主世界与下界维度
Now ruined portals are naturally generated nether portals
which spawn in both the overworld and the nether.
废弃传送门由普通黑曜石与新增的哭泣黑曜石构成
Ruined portals are made of normal obsidian and the
newly added crying obsidian which looks like this.
每个废弃传送门旁都会生成宝箱  内含各类金质物品以及用于建造传送门的材料
A chest also spawns with every ruined portal and you can
find various gold items and items used to build the portals
比如黑曜石和打火石等材料
such as obsidian and flint and steel.
需注意的是传送门上的哭泣黑曜石  在激活时不会产生作用
It's worth noting that the crying obsidian that generates on the
portal will not work when trying to activate it so you
必须用钻石镐将其破坏  并替换为普通黑曜石才能激活
will have to break it with a diamond pickaxe and replace it with normal obsidian.
不过收集哭泣黑曜石仍大有用途  因为在工作台中将其与荧石组合可以制作出
Collecting crying obsidian is still very useful though as
combining it with glowstone in the crafting table allows you
名为重生锚的新方块
to craft a new block called the respawn anchor.
重生锚的外观如图所示  它能让玩家在下界设置重生点  这一功能填补了游戏机制的空白
The respawn anchor looks like this and it allows the player
to set their spawn point in the nether which is a feature
我们期待已久的功能终于实现了
we've been waiting years for.
重生锚需要荧石充能  要手持荧石右键点击锚体即可为其注入能量
The respawn anchor is powered by glowstone which means if you right
click on the anchor with said glowstone it powers
该方块会获得一点充能
the block with one charge.
这意味着你现在可以右键点击重生锚  设置重生点  这样即使在下界死亡
This means you can now right click on the respawn anchor
and set your spawn point so if you die in the nether you'll
也能在重生锚处复活
respawn back at the block.
在重生锚复活后  该方块的充能等级会减一  你需要重新为其充能
Respawning at the respawn anchor will then decrease the charge of the block
by one which means you will have to power it
用荧石补充能量
again with glowstone.
需要注意的是 重生锚最多可储存四点充能  总共能获得四次重生机会
With that said a maximum of four charges can be set
on the respawn anchor giving you four different respawns at the block before needing to recharge it
若在下界死亡时重生锚未充能  你仍会在原始出生点复活
If you die in the nether without charging the respawn anchor
then you will of course respawn at your original spawn
主世界的原始重生点
point in the overworld.
在主世界或末地尝试使用重生锚  会导致该方块爆炸  并引燃周围所有可燃物
Attempting to use the respawn anchor in the overworld
or the end will result in the block exploding setting fire to all
所以除了下界之外  在其他维度使用这个方块大概率会让你当场去世
surrounding blocks so yeah you will more than likely
die using the block anywhere but the nether.
接下来在1.16版本中  新增了灵魂火  它的外观是这样的
Next up in 1.16 we have the addition of soul fire which looks like this.
灵魂火是普通火焰的蓝色变种  它会自然生成于我提到的灵魂沙峡谷生物群系
So soul fire is the blue variant of regular
fire and it naturally generates in the soul sand valley biome I mentioned earlier.
灵魂火可在任何维度生成  只要玩家用打火石点燃灵魂沙或灵魂土即可
Soul fire can be created in any dimension as long
as the player lights flint and steel on soul sand or soul soil.
灵魂火每秒会对玩家造成1颗心的伤害  而普通火焰每秒仅造成半颗心伤害
Soul fire deals a damage of one heart per second
to the player whereas normal fire only deals half a heart of damage per
因此灵魂火的致命性略高一筹
second so it's slightly more deadly.
还需注意的是  与普通火焰不同  灵魂火在雨中也不会熄灭  这特性相当酷
It's also worth noting that unlike normal fire
soul fire will not extinguish when it's in the rain which is really cool.
下界更新中新增了一个名为  灵魂疾行的附魔效果
In the nether update a new enchantment has been added which is called soul speed.
灵魂疾行附魔适用于靴子  能让玩家在灵魂沙上行走时加速
Now the soul speed enchant is used on boots
and it allows the player to walk faster on soul sand which is going to be
穿越下界时  这个附魔会非常实用
really useful for travelling in the nether.
灵魂疾行附魔书只能通过在堡垒遗迹的箱子中搜寻  或是通过
The soul speed enchanted book can only be obtained
by finding them in either a chest in a bastion remnant or by
与猪灵生物以物易物获得
bartering with a piglin mob.
下界更新新增的另一个特性  是名为磁石的方块  外观如图所示
The next feature added in the nether update is the addition of
a new block called lodestone which looks like this.
磁石由八个錾制石砖和一个下界合金锭合成  乍看之下它只是个
Lodestone is crafted with eight chiselled stone bricks
and one netherite ingot and at first glance it just looks like a
装饰性方块  但它实际功能远不止于此
decorative block but it does much more than that.
所以在下界中 普通指南针会
So a normal compass in the nether does,
完全失效
well, nothing.
它不会指向任何地方  只会漫无目的地旋转
It doesn't lead you to anywhere and it just spins around aimlessly.
但如果你用指南针  右键点击磁石方块  它就会开始发光并转变为磁石指南针
However if you right click on a lodestone block with a compass
it will start glowing and change into a lodestone compass.
现在 磁石指南针会始终指向磁石方块的位置  这在你于下界迷路时会非常有用
Now a lodestone compass will always point towards the lodestone block
making it very useful if you happen to get lost in the nether.
但如果你破坏了磁石方块  指南针就会再次失效
If you break the lodestone block though your compass will once again become useless.
下界更新后  灵魂沙可用于制作新型火把  名为灵魂火把  它看起来像这样
Soul sand in the nether update can now be used to make a new
type of torch called the soul torch and it looks like this.
灵魂火把的制作方式与普通火把类似  只是将木棍下方替换为灵魂沙
The soul torch is crafted similar to a normal torch except you place soul sand under the stick.
值得注意的是 灵魂火把的光照等级比普通火把更低  因此实用性稍逊
It's worth noting that soul torches give off a lower light level
than regular torches so they're not as good but they
但外观依然炫酷
still look awesome.
若你不想要灵魂火把  可以用它来制作新增的灵魂灯笼  看起来是这样的
If you don't want a soul torch you can use the soul torch to
craft the newly added soul lantern which looks like this.
只需将灵魂火把放在中间  周围围上铁粒  你就得到了灵魂灯笼
Just simply place a soul torch in the middle and surround it
with iron nuggets and bam you've got yourself a soul lantern.
在Minecraft 1.16版本中新增了锁链方块  其外观如图所示  制作配方为一个铁锭加两个铁粒
In Minecraft 1.16 chains have been added which look like this
and are crafted by using one iron ingot and two iron nuggets.
锁链是装饰性方块  可用于悬挂灯笼和钟  这正是许多玩家期待已久的功能
Chains are decorative blocks and can be used to hang lanterns
and bells which is a feature a lot of players were asking
如今这个功能终于实装了
for and now we have it.
在Minecraft 1.16版本中  新增了下界金矿石  这是金矿石的变种  外观如图所示
In Minecraft 1.16 nether gold ore has been added
which is a variant of gold ore and it looks like this.
用镐开采下界金矿石会掉落2到6个金粒  但时运附魔能提高掉落数量
Mining nether gold ore with a pickaxe will drop two to six gold nuggets
however the fortune enchantment can increase the drop rate.
使用精准采集镐开采下界金矿石
You can also mine nether gold ore with silk torch,
将矿石放入熔炉冶炼  即可获得一个金锭
smelt the ore in a furnace and get one gold ingot.
千万别在猪灵附近开采这种矿石  否则即便你穿着金质盔甲它们也会对你发动攻击
Don't get caught mining this ore near a piglin or
they will attack you even if you are wearing gold armor.
我忘记提到的另一个灵魂相关方块  是灵魂营火  它的外观如图所示
Another soul related block I forgot to mention is the soul campfire which looks like this.
灵魂营火的合成方式与普通营火类似  只是用灵魂沙替代了煤炭
Now again soul campfires are crafted similar to normal
campfires except they use soul sand instead of coal.
我之前提到的猪灵生物会主动避开灵魂火
The piglin mobs I mentioned earlier will avoid soul fire,
灵魂火把 灵魂灯笼和灵魂营火  都能有效驱避猪灵  这些方块堪称对抗猪灵的神器
soul torches, soul lanterns and soul campfires making them very useful to counter piglins.
在1.16版本更新中  我们熟知的僵尸猪人  已被僵尸猪灵取代  它们的行为模式完全一致
In the 1.16 update the zombie pigmen we know
and love have been replaced by zombified piglins which behave exactly the
只不过它们现在是猪灵的僵尸变种
same as zombie pigmen did but yeah they're just the zombie counterpart of piglins.
安息吧 最初的僵尸猪人  我们会永远怀念你们
Rest in peace original zombie pigmen you will be missed.
哦 如果猪灵遇到它们的僵尸变种  它们会立即避开并逃跑
Oh if piglins happen to encounter their zombie counterpart then they will avoid them and run away.
看来它们害怕自己也会变成僵尸  这种恐惧确实合情合理
I guess they're scared to become one of them which makes sense to be honest.
随着每次我的世界版本更新  现在主界面标题画面已更换为下界更新主题  看起来焕然一新
With every Minecraft update now the title screen has been changed to have a
theme for the nether update and it looks like this.
你在我的世界加载界面看到的Mojang标志也在1.16版本更新了  现在变成了这样
The Mojang logo that you see on the loading screen
for Minecraft has also been changed in 1.16 and it looks like this.
我很喜欢这个新设计
I quite like it.
在视频结束前  我要补充介绍1.16版本新增的所有未被提及的新方块
Before this video ends I'm going to mention all the new
blocks that were added in 1.16 that I have not yet mentioned.
首先登场的是黑石  它看起来是这样的  这是圆石的另一种变体  可以用来制作与石头相关的工具
First up we have blackstone which looks like this
and is another variant of cobblestone as you can craft stone related tools with it
除此之外  我们还有磨制黑石
On top of that we have polished blackstone,
錾制磨制黑石
chiseled polished blackstone,
磨制黑石砖  以及裂纹磨制黑石砖
polished blackstone brick and cracked polished blackstone bricks.
此外还有三种黑石墙
We also have 3 types of blackstone walls,
三种黑石台阶
3 types of blackstone stairs,
三种黑石板  一个黑石压力板  以及黑石按钮
3 types of slabs, a pressure plate and a button.
还有这种镶金黑石  挖掘时可能直接掉落方块  也可能掉落2-5个金粒
There's also this gilded blackstone where if mined
will either give you the block back or 2-5 gold nuggets.
在下界更新中新增了錾制下界砖 仔细观察你会发现
Chiseled nether bricks have been added in the nether update and if you
look closely you'll notice it has the face of a
砖块上刻着凋灵骷髅的脸 这设计相当酷炫
wither skeleton on it which is really cool.
我开头提到的绯红森林生物群系能让你获取绯红菌柄  进而制成绯红木板
The crimson forest biome I mentioned at the start allows you
to obtain crimson stem which you can get crimson planks from.
扭曲森林生物群系  同样能获取扭曲菌柄  也可用于制作木板
The warped forest biome also allows you to get warped stems which you can also get planks from.
关于绯红与诡异木板  有个特别之处在于它们不像普通木板  完全无法被烧毁
An interesting thing to note about crimson and warped planks is
that unlike normal wooden planks they cannot burn which
非常实用
is great.
绯红与诡异木板  也能用于制作台阶
Crimson and warped planks can also be used to make slabs,
楼梯  栅栏  栅栏门
stairs, fences, fence gates,
压力板  按钮
pressure plates, buttons,
告示牌  活板门  以及门
signs, trapdoors and doors.
想要重新长出绯红和诡异菌柄  只需对着绯红菌和诡异菌使用骨粉就能轻松搞定
If you want to regrow crimson and warped stems just simply use bone
meal on crimson and warped fungi and there you go.
最后还有 疣猪兽会跳舞！
And finally, hoglins can dance!
今天为大家盘点我的世界1.17版本新增的100项内容
Today I bring you 100 things that were added in Minecraft 1.17.
本视频将全面介绍所有新增生物群系
In this video I'll be covering all the new biomes,
全新生物  新增物品  以及洞穴与山崖更新中更多精彩内容
the new mobs, the new items and much much more in the caves and cliffs update.
值得注意的是 这是洞穴与山崖更新的第一部分 部分特性已推迟至1.18版本更新的第二部分加入
It's worth noting that this is part 1 of the caves and cliffs update as some
features have been postponed to be added in part 2 for the 1.18 update.
好了 视频正式开始
Anyways, on with the video.
1.17洞穴与山崖更新的首个新增内容便是深层板岩方块的加入
The first feature added in the 1.17 caves and cliffs update is the addition of the deepslate block.
深层板岩是一种深灰色岩石 它会在Y坐标0至16层之间的洞穴中自然生成
So deepslate is a dark grey stone that looks like this
and it generates in caves between levels 0 and 16.
深层板岩的挖掘耗时比普通石头更长  使用任意镐类工具开采时会掉落深板岩圆石
Now deepslate takes longer to mine than stone and drops
cobbled deepslate when mined with any pickaxe.
不仅新增了深层板岩  1.17版本还加入了深板岩矿石变种
Not only did we get deepslate in 1.17 but we also got deepslate ores.
深板岩矿石包含了主世界所有矿石的变种  比如铁矿石
Now the deepslate ores are variants of all the overworld ores including iron,
黄金  钻石  红石
gold, diamond, redstone,
绿宝石  青金石  以及新加入的铜矿石  它们的外观都呈现这种形态
emerald, lapis and the newly added copper ore and all of them look like this.
深板岩矿石与普通矿石的主要区别仅在于 其开采耗时是后者的两倍 所以挖起来会更费劲一些
Now there's not much difference between the deepslate ores and regular ores other than
the fact that they take twice as long to mine than the normal ores so uh yeah it's a bit more painful.
接下来要介绍的洞穴更新特性  是对我的世界矿石系统的重大玩法调整
The next feature we have in the cave update is a big gameplay change
that has been made to ores in minecraft.
因此在1.17版本中开采铁矿石等矿物时  将不再直接掉落矿石本身 而是会给予玩家一种新物品 名为粗铁
So in 1.17 mining ores like iron ore for example no longer drops
the ore itself and instead gives the player a new item known as raw iron.
粗铁的功能与原版铁矿石相同  放入熔炉冶炼后依然能获得铁锭
So raw iron functions the as the iron ore block
does as when you smelt it in a furnace it still gives you an iron ingot.
值得注意的是  普通铁矿石仍可熔炼成锭  开发者并未移除该功能
It's worth noting that you can still smelt regular iron ore
for the ingots so yeah they didn't remove it.
接下来介绍1.17洞穴与山崖更新中新增的两种生物群系
Next up in the 1.17 caves and cliffs update we have the addition of two new biomes.
严格来说是两种变体
Well sort of.
首先是繁茂洞穴生物群系  其景观如图所示
So the first biome we have is the lush cave biome which looks like this.
是不是美不胜收？
Isn't it beautiful?
繁茂洞穴由多种新方块构成  比如这种苔藓块
So lush caves are composed of many new blocks such as the moss block which looks like this.
这里还生长着发光浆果藤蔓  既能发光又可食用  相当实用
It also has vines that contain glow berries
which emit light and can be used as a food item which is quite nice.
洞穴内还有一种滴水叶方块  专为跑酷和平台跳跃设计
The lush cave also contains a block called the drip leaf
which is intended to be used for parkour and platforming.
另外要注意的是  在滴水叶上站立过久叶片会因承重而塌陷 导致玩家坠落 务必小心
Oh and standing on a drip leaf too long will cause it to
give way resulting in you falling through it so be careful.
这个美丽的生物群系还包含杜鹃花丛  使用骨粉可以将其培育成全新的杜鹃花树
The lovely biome also contains azalea blocks
which can be grown into the new azalea trees with the use of bone meal and they look like this.
不过在1.17版本中  繁茂洞穴目前只能通过创建世界时 选择单一生物群系选项才能体验
However currently in 1.17 the lush caves can only be accessed
if you select the single biome world option when creating a world.
这是因为该生物群系尚未完成 且Minecraft计划在1.18版本中全面加入以实现自然生成
This is because the biome is not yet fully completed
and Minecraft plans to fully add the biome to generate naturally in 1.18.
接下来要介绍的是1.17版本中的滴水石洞穴生物群系
The next biome we sort of have in 1.17 is the dripstone caves biome.
与繁茂洞穴相同目前只能通过 创建单一生物群系世界才能体验这个洞穴
Now just like the lush caves you can only access this
biome by generating a world with the single biome world type selected.
现在看到的便是滴水石洞穴群系  其顶部与底部都会自然生成尖锐的滴水石
Now the dripstone caves biome looks like this and it
contains pointed dripstone that generates on the ceiling and on the ground.
现在如果玩家落在尖锐滴水石上就会受到伤害  务必小心
Now the player will take damage if they land on pointed dripstone so be careful.
该生物群系将在1.18版本正式加入  现在让我们继续介绍其他内容
But yeah the dripstone caves biome won't properly be added until
part 2 of the caves and cliffs update which is in version 1.18 so let's move on.
接下来要介绍的是1.17版本中正式加入的新生物——美西螈
The next feature that we did properly get in the 1.17 update is
the addition of a new mob which is the axolotl.
美西螈是一种水生被动型生物自然生成于水域中  每次会以1-4只的群体形式出现
Now the axolotl is an aquatic passive mob
that of course spawns in water and it spawns in groups of one to four.
美西螈共有五种体色  分别是粉色
So axolotls come in five different colours which are pink,
棕色 金色 青色和蓝色
brown, gold, cyan and blue.
蓝色变种的美西螈极为罕见  生成概率仅有1/1200
The blue variety of axolotl is very rare as it only has a 1 in 1,200
若你发现了蓝色美西螈  记得在评论区告诉我
chance of spawning so please let me know in the comments if you find one.
美西螈可以用热带鱼繁殖  它们会攻击除海龟和海豚外的所有水生生物
Axolotls can also be bred with tropical fish
and they will attack all aquatic mobs except turtles and dolphins.
所以美西螈会帮你解决那些烦人的溺尸  这真是太棒了
So yeah axolotls will take care of the stupid drowned mobs for you which will be lovely.
如果你击杀了与美西螈交战中的生物 你将获得持续1分钟的生命恢复I效果
However with that said if you kill a mob that an
axolotl is in combat with then you'll receive the regeneration 1 effect which is nice.
美西螈可以用水桶捕获 就像捕鱼一样 如果将它们放在陆地上 五分钟后它们会逐渐脱水并开始受到伤害
Axolotls can be caught by using a water bucket just like fish and if you put
them on land they'll eventually dry out and start taking damage after five minutes.
各位千万别学我这样做  我纯粹是为了拍视频才不得已为之  看着美西螈死去实在太令人心碎了
Please don't do this guys I had to do it for the sake of the video
but an axolotl dying is just it's just very sad to watch.
接下来要介绍的是1.17洞穴与山崖更新中加入的新生物——山羊
The next mob that was added in the 1.17 caves and cliffs update is the addition of the goat.
没错各位  现在游戏里真的加入山羊了
Yep that's right guys we have goats now.
山羊的外形是这样的  它们只会在山地生物群系中生成
So the goat looks like this and they can only be found in mountain biomes.
山羊能跳跃高达10格以跨越地形障碍  比如地面上的沟壑
Goats are able to jump up to 10 blocks high
to avoid obstacles such as a gap in the terrain for example.
不过山羊有个特殊能力  从高处坠落时受到的摔落伤害比其他生物要低得多
However if a goat happens to fall then they will take a reduced
fall damage compared to all the other mobs in Minecraft.
所以山羊从很高处坠落时也能安然无恙
So yeah goats are able to fall from a pretty high height and survive.
山羊属于中立型生物  它们只会在特定情况下攻击玩家
Now goats are considered neutral mobs as they will only attack you under certain circumstances.
如果玩家在山羊附近停留超过一定时间山羊就会发动冲撞攻击
So if the player is standing within proximity of a
goat for a certain amount of time then a goat will charge at the
玩家会被顶飞  最远能击退九格距离  这威力确实不容小觑
player ramming them up to a distance of nine blocks which is quite a lot actually.
山羊对其他生物  也会发动这种冲撞攻击
Goats are also able to do this to other mobs in Minecraft.
说实话 山羊有时候还挺暴躁的
So yeah goats can just be a bit mean to be honest.
用小麦可以繁殖山羊 也可以拿着桶右键点击山羊就能获得羊奶
Goats can be bred by using wheat and you can also right click on a goat with a bucket to obtain milk.
第三个也是1.17洞穴与山崖更新中最后加入的生物是——发光鱿鱼
The third and final mob that was added in the 1.17 caves and cliffs update is the glow squid.
它们生成在水下  行为与普通鱿鱼类似  但特殊之处在于它们身上带有这些酷炫的发光粒子效果
Now the glow squid looks like this and it spawns underwater and behaves just like
a regular squid except they have these cool glowing particles emitting from them.
不仅如此  发光鱿鱼还会掉落一种独特的新物品——荧光墨囊
Not only that but glow squids will drop a new unique item known as glow ink sacks.
荧光墨囊的妙处在于  它能与物品展示框在工作台中合成制作出会发光的物品展示框
Now the glow ink sacks are quite cool as they can be combined
with an item frame in a crafting table to make a glowing item frame.
这种发光物品展示框是1.17新增的展示框变种
Now the glow item frame is a new variant of the item frame added in 1.17 and it's in the name really.
放置时会发出亮光
When you place it it appears lit up.
更棒的是  放入展示框的物品也会跟着发光
On top of that the items you put inside the item frame also light up as well which is awesome.
不过奇怪的是  发光物品展示框并不会照亮周围方块仅仅是自身显示为发光状态
Weirdly though the glowing item frame doesn't emit light to surrounding blocks it just appears lit.
话说回来 我们继续
Anyways moving on.
接下来要介绍的是Minecraft 1.17新增的一种全新结构——紫水晶洞窟
The next feature added in Minecraft 1.17 is
the addition of a new structure known as the amethyst geodes.
这些晶洞通常生成于地下  但偶尔也会罕见地裸露在地表之上
So the geodes are uncommonly found underground but can also rarely be exposed at the surface.
紫水晶洞窟内含有两种紫水晶方块  分别是紫水晶芽和普通紫水晶
So amethyst geodes contain two amethyst blocks
which are the budding amethyst and the normal amethyst.
普通紫水晶方块它只是个装饰性方块  但用镐开采时可以完整采集到
The normal amethyst block looks like this and it's just a decorative block
but it can be obtained when you mine it with a pickaxe.
而紫水晶芽块则是这般模样  被破坏时无法获取  但它会生长出这些晶体状的
The budding amethyst however looks like this and cannot be
obtained when destroyed but it will grow these crystal like
碎片状物体  也就是我们所说的紫水晶簇
shards which are known as amethyst clusters.
紫水晶簇最初以紫水晶芽的形态存在并会分阶段生长
So the amethyst clusters start off as an amethyst bud and they grow in stages.
当它生长到最终阶段时用镐开采可以获得四个紫水晶碎片
Once it reaches its final growth stage you can mine it with a pickaxe to obtain four amethyst shards.
目前在Minecraft 1.17版本中紫水晶碎片可用于三种合成配方  其一就是我刚才展示过的
Currently in Minecraft 1.17 the amethyst shard is used in three
crafting recipes which is the amethyst block I showed
紫水晶块  还有新增的望远镜以及染色玻璃  接下来我就详细讲解这些物品的用途
you earlier, the new spy glass and the new tinted glass and I'll talk about those now.
洞穴与山崖更新中新增的下一个特性就是望远镜的加入
So the next feature added in caves and cliffs is the addition of the spy glass.
望远镜的外观是这样的  制作配方需要一个紫水晶碎片  加上两个新增的铜锭
The spy glass looks like this and is crafted with one amethyst shard
and two of the newly added copper ingots.
这个望远镜比较简陋 因为它的作用只是让你能放大观察某个特定地点
Now the spy glass is essentially just a telescope in Minecraft
to be honest as you can just use it to zoom in on a specific location.
接下来要介绍的是遮光玻璃  它的外观如图所示
Next up we have tinted glass which looks like this.
遮光玻璃的合成配方是四个紫水晶碎片加一块普通玻璃
Again, tinted glass is crafted with four amethyst shards
and one glass and it's a unique type of glass and here's why.
遮光玻璃放置后虽然玩家视角下看起来是透明的  但实际上它能完全阻隔所有光线
So the tinted glass when placed remains visually transparent to the player
but it actually blocks out all light which I
相信这个特性会成为玩家手中非常实用的建筑方块
think will serve as quite a useful block for players.
我是说如果你想造个带窗户的房子  但又想保持室内完全黑暗  那么在1.17版本中这个愿望可以实现啦
I mean if you want to make a house with windows but live in complete
darkness then you can now do that in 1.17.
Minecraft 1.17版本新增的下一个特性就是加入了全新的矿石  当然就是铜矿石啦
The next feature added in Minecraft 1.17 is the addition of
a new ore which is of course copper ore.
铜矿石的外观如图所示它能在主世界的任何高度生成
So copper ore looks like this and it can generate anywhere in the overworld.
开采铜矿石时会掉落2-3个粗铜  这和铁矿的机制类似
When copper ore is mined it drops two to three raw copper similar to iron ore.
粗铜当然可以放进熔炉冶炼  最终得到铜锭
Then the raw copper can of course be smelted in a furnace to give you copper ingots.
还要提醒大家的是铜矿石也有深层变种  就像其他深层矿石一样
I should also mention to you all that there's a deep slate
copper ore variant and just like the rest of the deep slate
开采耗时是普通铜矿石的两倍
ores it takes twice as long to mine than the regular copper ore.
用铜锭可以合成铜块  它的外观长这样
With your copper ingots you can craft copper blocks which look like this.
不仅如此你还可以用铜块来合成切制铜块  这是铜块的精细版本
Not only that but you can also use copper blocks to craft
cut copper which is the more detailed version of copper blocks.
对了 切制铜块还能做成楼梯和台阶  看起来也超级棒
Oh and cut copper also has stairs and slabs which look very nice as well.
就像现实世界一样  我刚才提到的所有铜块都会随着时间慢慢氧化
However one thing to note just like in real life all these copper blocks
I mentioned will oxidize over time in your Minecraft world.
铜会经历四个氧化阶段  颜色会逐渐改变
So copper will oxidize and change color in four stages.
它会从普通铜块开始氧化
It will start off as the normal copper,
接着会变成斑驳铜块
it will then become exposed copper,
随后会变成风化铜块  最终氧化为锈蚀铜块
then weathered copper and finally oxidized copper which looks like this.
不过别担心  如果你不想让铜块随时间氧化这里有个解决办法
But don't worry guys if you don't want your copper to oxidize over time then there is a solution.
在工作台上将铜块与蜜脾结合就能制作出涂蜡铜块
So if you combine copper with honeycomb in a crafting table then you'll actually create waxed copper.
涂蜡铜块其实就是普通铜块的变种  只不过它不会随时间氧化变色
Now waxed copper is just a variant of normal copper except it will not oxidize over time and change color.
1.17洞穴与山崖更新中新增的另一个物品是蜡烛
The next thing added in the 1.17 caves and cliffs update is the addition of candles.
蜡烛是我的世界中的光源分为未染色版本和16种染色版本
So the candle is a light source in Minecraft that exists in an uncolored variant and 16 dyed variants.
如果你好奇的话  它们看起来都是这样的
And if you were curious they all look like this.
蜡烛的合成配方是一个蜜脾加一根线 用打火石即可点燃
Candles are crafted with one honeycomb and one string and are lit by using flint and steel.
蜡烛也能被水浇灭或者直接右键点击即可熄灭
They can also be put out by water or you can just right click on it.
单根蜡烛的光照等级为3级  但单个方块最多可放置4根蜡烛最高能提供12级的光照强度
A single candle emits a light level of three but up to four candles
can be placed in a single block giving you a max light level of 12.
单根蜡烛还能插在未食用的蛋糕上  这意味着现在你可以在游戏里正经地庆祝生日了
A single candle can also be placed on an uneaten cake
which means you can celebrate properly in Minecraft now.
好吧 刚才有点尴尬
Okay that was a bit cringe anyways,
继续吧
moving on.
在我的世界1.17版本中下雪时炼药锅会逐渐积雪
In Minecraft 1.17 cauldrons will slowly fill up when it's snowing,
就像雨天时炼药锅会积水那样
similar to how cauldrons collect water when it rains.
随后你可以用桶收集锅中的雪  获得装有细雪的桶  这种桶可以用于
You can then use a bucket to collect the snow from the cauldron giving the
player a powder snow bucket which can be used
放置新增的细雪方块  其外观与普通雪块极为相似
to place the newly added powdered snow block which looks very similar to regular snow.
但细雪与普通雪截然不同  玩家可以穿行其中  甚至可能直接陷落下去
However powdered snow differs greatly to normal snow as
players can walk through it and also fall through it.
这使得这个方块非常实用 因为将其与普通雪块混在一起 能很好地隐藏你的箱子避开其他玩家的视线
This makes the block quite useful as blending it in with normal snow makes it a
great way to hide your chest in a secret space from other players.
细雪还能用来制作熔岩陷阱  同样可以将其与普通雪块混合  在游戏世界中布下致命机关 看起来毫无破绽
Powdered snow can also be used to create lava traps as again
you can blend it in with normal snow to make the world terrain look well normal.
玩家走过细雪区域
A player will then walk over the powdered snow,
陷入熔岩而丧命
fall in lava and die.
现在会感受到冰冻效果 当站在粉雪中时屏幕上会出现 炫酷的冰冻视觉效果同时视野范围也会逐渐缩小
Players can now freeze in Minecraft as standing inside powdered snow will put this cool looking
freezing effect on screen while also slowly decreasing the field of view.
在细雪中站立15秒后  生命值会变成这种结霜纹理  同时你将开始受到伤害
After 15 seconds of standing inside powdered snow the player's
heart will change to this frosty texture and you'll take
每三秒损失半颗心的生命值  直到最终被彻底冻死
half a heart of damage every three seconds until you eventually freeze to death.
不过只要穿戴任意一件皮革护甲 就能防止玩家站在细雪中时被冻死
However wearing any piece of leather armor will prevent the player from
freezing when standing inside the powdered snow.
确实相当酷炫
Very cool indeed.
因为“酷”和“冻”...我们继续
Because cool and freezing to... moving on.
我的世界1.18版本新增的50项内容
50 things that were added in Minecraft 1.18.
总之 我们开始吧
Anyways here we go.
在我的世界1.18洞穴与山崖更新中游戏的高度限制已正式调整
In the Minecraft 1.18 caves and cliffs update the height limit has officially been changed.
这意味着新的高度范围向上扩展64格 向下延伸64格最高可达320层  而最低可挖至负64层
This means the new height expands 64 blocks up and 64 blocks down with 320
being the height limit upwards and minus 64 being the limit downwards.
这使得1.18版本的总高度限制达到384格  而此前1.17及更早版本的高度限制仅为256格
This completes the overall height limit to 384 blocks
in 1.18 whereas before 1.18 the height limit was 256 blocks.
此外 云层高度也相应提升了
On top of this the cloud height has also been increased.
因此在我的世界1.18版本之前云层高度仅为128格  但在1.18版本中  这一高度被提升到了192格高
So before Minecraft 1.18 the cloud height was 128 blocks high
but in Minecraft 1.18 it's been increased to 192 blocks high.
在我的世界1.18版本中使用藏宝图找到的埋藏宝箱 现在有几率开出水下呼吸药水
In Minecraft 1.18 the buried treasure chest that you find
with a map now have a chance to contain a water breathing
极大助力你在本次更新中的水下洞穴探险
potion which will be very helpful for your underwater cave exploring in this update.
安东尼 你声音破音得真可爱
Nice voice crack Anthony.
言归正传
Anyways moving on.
在我的世界中玩家偶尔会遇到由骨块和煤矿石构成的化石结构
In Minecraft players can rarely encounter fossils
which are structures that are made of bone blocks and coal ore.
然而在我的世界1.18版本中  若在Y坐标负63至
However in Minecraft 1.18 a change was made to
where if you find a fossil that's generated between y levels minus 63 to
负8区间内生成的化石  其中的煤矿石将被钻石矿石取代
minus 8 you'll find diamond ore within the fossil instead of coal ore.
没错 现在你甚至能在化石里挖到钻石  简直太棒了
So yeah, you can find some diamonds within the fossils which is awesome.
在我的世界1.18版本之前 唤魔者
Before Minecraft 1.18 evokers,
掠夺者和卫道士  会攻击并杀死幼年村民  这种场面实在令人心碎
pillagers and vindicators would attack and kill baby villagers
which was just very sad to witness.
但在我的世界1.18版本中  这些烦人的怪物现在会放过幼年村民了
However in Minecraft 1.18 a change was made to where these
annoying mobs would leave the baby villagers alone which
这让它们总算没那么招人厌了
makes them slightly less annoying I suppose.
在我的世界1.18版本中  繁茂洞穴生物群系现已能自然生成于游戏世界
In Minecraft 1.18 the beautiful lush cave biome is now able to
generate naturally in your Minecraft world.
1.18版本之前繁茂洞穴生物群系仅限单一生物群系 世界类型使用 这设定实在有些鸡肋
Before 1.18 the lush cave biome was only available in the
single biome world type option which was a bit rubbish so it's
现在探索时就能遇见  真是太棒了
awesome that we can now find it while exploring.
不仅如此在我的世界1.18版本中 还新增了著名的滴水石洞穴生物群系
Not only that but in Minecraft 1.18 we have also received
the infamous dripstone cave biome which looks like this.
这个生物群系虽在1.17版本加入  但此前无法在常规世界生成  如今终得实现 实在令人欣喜
Now again this biome was added in 1.17 but wasn't available
in normal Minecraft world so I'm very happy I can now land
探索时一头栽进滴水石锥堆里送命
on lots of pointed dripstone and die while exploring.
在我的世界1.18版本中  可爱的美西螈生物也迎来了改动
In Minecraft 1.18 a change has been made to the adorable axolotl mobs.
因此在1.17版本中  美西螈会生成于任何含水体的生物群系不论是浩瀚的海洋
So in 1.17 axolotls would spawn in any biome of
the Minecraft world that contained water whether it would be a massive
还是小小水洼
ocean or a small looking lake.
但在1.18版本中  美西螈仅会生成于新增的繁茂洞穴生物群系水域
However in 1.18 axolotls will now only spawn in water that is within the newly added lush cave biome.
我十分赞同这项改动  因为美西螈本就该只生成于繁茂洞穴  如今我们终于能在自然探索中发现这个生物群系
I'm a fan of this change as axolotls were always intended
to only spawn in lush caves so now that we can find the biome
这个改动确实合情合理
naturally this change makes sense.
在我的世界1.18版本中  世界生成机制迎来了全面革新
In Minecraft 1.18 the world generation has been completely overhauled.
这意味着你将邂逅这些壮丽的全新山脉  或是平滑如砥的地形景观  视觉效果惊艳绝伦
This means you will encounter these new stunning looking mountains
or smooth areas of terrain which look absolutely amazing.
在我的世界1.18版本中  马匹也迎来了一项小改动
In Minecraft 1.18 a small little change has been made with horses.
在洞穴与山崖第二部分更新中马匹现在会跟随手持 金胡萝卜、金苹果或附魔金苹果的玩家
That's right in caves and cliffs part 2 horses will now follow players
when they are holding golden carrots,golden apples and enchanted golden apples.
对不起了马儿  这颗附魔金苹果你想都别想
I'm sorry horse there is absolutely no chance you are getting this enchanted golden apple.
我费了九牛二虎之力才得到它
It took me so long to obtain.
我是说在创造模式里  输入附魔金苹果  再切回生存模式给自己  这容易吗我
I mean come on I had to type enchanted golden apple in the
creative inventory and give it to myself in survival.
可费了我老大劲了
It was a lot of effort.
在洞穴与山崖更新中  附魔台迎来了一项细微调整
In the caves and cliffs update the enchanting table has received a slight change.
在1.18版本中附魔台现在会发出7级亮度  而在此次更新前它完全不发光
That's right in 1.18 the enchanting table will now
emit a light level of 7 whereas before this update it didn't emit any light.
基岩版早就有这功能了  但至少Java版现在也有了
I know I know bedrock edition has had this feature for years but at least Java has it now.
1.18版本有个值得注意的变化  世界生成不再依赖于生物群系
An interesting change to note in 1.18 is that the world generation is no longer biome dependent.
这意味着全面改进的世界生成 将适用于所有生物群系  从此你的世界里处处都能领略到
This means the overhauled world generation will spread across every
biome in your world meaning you'll be able to
这些惊艳的新山脉景观
experience these amazing new mountains in any biome which is very lovely.
在Minecraft 1.18版本之前  玩家只要在床上睡一觉就能随时重置天气循环
Before Minecraft 1.18 players could reset the weather cycle at any time when they slept in a bed.
但在Minecraft 1.18版本中  调整为仅在下雨或雷暴天气时睡觉  才能重置天气循环
However in Minecraft 1.18 a change was made to where sleeping
only resets the weather cycle if the weather is raining or if a thunderstorm is occurring.
这意味着世界将迎来更多降雨天气  因为睡觉不再能重置天气循环
This means you can expect more rain occur in your Minecraft world
as sleeping in a bed isn't going to reset the cycle every time.
在Minecraft 1.18版本中玩家在世界中的生成机制发生了改变
In Minecraft 1.18 a change was made to how the player can spawn in a Minecraft world.
在1.18版本之前  玩家创建世界时有可能出生在海洋里  或其他不方便的位置
So before 1.18 when the player created a world
they had a chance to spawn in the ocean or another inconvenient location
比如出生在岩浆池里
like spawning in a lava pool.
但在1.18版本更新中  世界出生算法经过重新设计  确保玩家总能出生在
However in the 1.18 update the world spawn algorithm has been
reworked meaning the player should always spawn in a
世界中的正常区域
normal spot within a world.
说实话 我可能会有点怀念  那种在茫茫大海中无依无靠的出生体验
I'm not gonna lie, I'm gonna kinda miss spawning in the middle of nowhere in an ocean,
确实挺有趣的
it was quite funny.
由于Minecraft 1.18版本中  世界生成机制的改变  村庄结构会变得略微罕见
Due to the world generation changes in Minecraft 1.18
the village structures will be slightly more rare to find due to
村庄建筑在Minecraft世界中  彼此间隔更远  因此出现频率会有所降低
them being spread out further from each other in your Minecraft world.
我认为这是个很好的改动  因为找到村庄并与这些可爱的村民交易绿宝石会更有成就感
I think this is a good change as it will feel more rewarding
to find a village and trade emeralds with these beautiful villagers.
你喜欢这个新的世界生成机制吗？
Are you liking this new world generation mate?
哦 你想让我走开？
Oh, you want me to go away?
好的
Okay.
如今每次Minecraft更新  1.18洞穴与山崖第二部分的标题画面都会随之改变
With every Minecraft update nowadays the title screen
for the 1.18 caves and calyphs part 2 has been changed to reflect
这意味着你会在背景中  看到许多壮观的山脉
the update theme which means you'll see a bunch of cool mountains in the background.
我很喜欢  看起来很有山脉特色
I like it, it looks very mountain-y.
好了 我们继续
Anyways, moving on.
在Minecraft 1.18版本中  对铜矿石进行了一个小改动
In Minecraft 1.18 a small change has been made to copper ore.
因此在1.17版本中用镐开采铜矿石会掉落2到3个粗铜 而在本次更新中开采铜矿石将给予玩家2到5个粗铜
So in 1.17 copper ore dropped 2 to 3 raw copper when it was mined with a pickaxe
whereas in this update copper ore gives the player 2 to 5 raw copper when mined.
好了 以上就是全部内容
Well there you have it,
相信很多铜矿爱好者  听到这个消息都会很开心
I'm sure a lot of copper lovers are going to be very happy about that.
在繁茂洞穴生物群系中  玩家会遇到这些看起来像这样的洞穴藤蔓
In the lush cave biome the player can encounter these cave vines that look like this.
这种洞穴藤蔓最高可生长至26格  并且有1/9的概率结出发光浆果
Now this cave vine can grow to a max height of 26 blocks
and has a 1 in 9 chance of growing with glowberries attached to them.
在1.18版本之前  这些洞穴藤蔓会不受控制地生长  除非你摧毁源头  否则无法阻止它们蔓延
Now before 1.18 these cave vines would grow uncontrollably
with no way of stopping them unless you destroyed the source block.
不过在Minecraft 1.18版本中  玩家可以通过剪除洞穴藤蔓的末梢来阻止其继续生长
However in Minecraft 1.18 a change was made to where the
player can shear the tip of the cave vine to stop it growing any further.
在Minecraft 1.18版本中  对美丽但有时恼人的沙漠神殿做出了一些改动
In Minecraft 1.18 a change has been made to the beautiful yet sometimes annoying desert pyramids.
所以在1.18版本之前  沙漠神殿有机会生成在水面上  看起来既炫酷又有些随性
So before 1.18 desert pyramids had a chance to generate on water which looked pretty cool and a bit random.
但在1.18版本中进行了调整  沙漠神殿将不再生成在水面上  而是会被强制生成在陆地表面
However in 1.18 a change was made to where desert pyramids
will no longer generate on water and will instead be forced to spawn on the surface.
丛林神殿同样如此  在1.18版本之前它们可能生成在水面上  但在1.18版本中这一设定已被移除
Jungle temples, same deal in 1.18 they used to be able to
generate on water but in 1.18 they no longer do so rest in
水上神殿  就此永眠
peace water spawning temples and pyramids,
我们会想念它们的
you will be missed.
在我的世界1.18版本中  游戏新增了一张全新音乐唱片  这张名为“Otherside”的唱片
In Minecraft 1.18 a brand new music disc has been added into the game
and said disc is called Otherside which looks like this.
这张全新加入的音乐唱片极少数情况下  能在要塞走廊的宝箱中找到
Now this newly added music disc can rarely be found
in chests within the corridors of a stronghold which is very lovely.
玩家也有机会在地牢宝箱中发现“Otherside”音乐唱片  只不过出现概率要低得多
The player is also able to find the Otherside music disc within
dungeon chests although it is a lot rarer to encounter this.
不过关于唱片稀有度的话题就到此为止
But enough of the music disc's rarity,
稍微听一下片段
here's a quick clip of how it sounds.
还有件事值得一提  “Otherside”唱片是我的世界中第二张并非由C418创作的唱片
Oh and another thing I thought I'd mention is that the Otherside music disc
is the second disc in Minecraft that is not composed by C418.
相反这张唱片由Lena Raine创作 她同时也是标志性唱片“Pigstep”的作曲者该唱片于1.16下界更新中加入
Instead the music disc is composed by Lena Rain who also composed
the iconic Pigstep music disc that was added in the 1.16 Nether update.
由于洞穴生成机制在1.18版本中被彻底重做并大幅扩展  游戏对标志性的地牢结构也做出了相应调整
Due to the cave generation being completely overhauled and expanded in 1.18
some changes have been made to the iconic dungeon structure.
可惜我无法告诉各位1.18版本在地牢外观上做出了改动  实际上变化主要体现在
Now I wish I could sit here and tell you guys that they've visually
changed the dungeons in 1.18 but instead the amount
地牢的生成数量有所增加  以配合新版巨型洞穴系统的规模
of dungeons that generate in your world have been increased
to coincide with the new giant cave systems.
所以没错 在1.18版本中  你会发现地牢数量明显增多了
So yeah, expect to find more dungeons in 1.18.
今天为大家盘点我的世界1.19版本新增的100项内容
Today I bring you 100 things that were added in Minecraft 1.19.
本期视频将全面介绍荒野更新中新增的所有生物群系
In this video I'll be covering all the new biomes,
新生物新物品等海量内容
the new mobs, the new items and much much more in the wild update.
话不多说 马上开始
Anyways, here we go.
1.19荒野更新的首个新特性是加入了带箱子的船
The first feature added in the 1.19 wild update is the addition of
a new boat type known as the boat with a chest.
在工作台用船和箱子合成  就能让你在航行时
That's right, combining a boat and chest in a crafting table
allows you to travel across water in a boat while storing
通过船上箱子储存更多物品
additional items in a chest.
可以说这简直是“船箱合璧”
You could say this item is the best.
“船”和“箱子”组合就是“最佳”？
Combine the words boat and chest and you get best?
大概吧...
Sort of?
我们继续
Let's just move on.
荒野更新的下一项内容是一种名为红树林的新树种
The next addition to the wild update is a new tree type that is known as the mangrove tree.
红树林树木呈现出与其他树木截然不同的独特形态
So the mangrove tree looks like this displaying a unique shape compared to other trees in Minecraft.
红树林还由这些被称为红树根的新方块支撑 它们与叶子极为相似
Mangrove trees are also supported by these new blocks known as mangrove roots which closely resemble leaves.
与其他树木一样红树木原木可加工成木板 进而为玩家
Like all trees, mangrove logs which look beautiful by
the way can be crafted into planks which can then give the player
提供衍生方块，如台阶
the respective blocks such as slabs,
台阶 楼梯 船只等各种衍生品
stairs, boats and much much more.
红树林叶片上会结出树苗  名为“红树胎生苗”
Mangrove trees can also generate with mangrove propagules attached to the leaves.
和普通树苗一样种植  最终会长成红树
These propagules can be planted just like saplings and will eventually
grow into a mangrove tree
若嫌长得太慢  撒点骨粉就行
but if it's taking too long just use some bone meal.
1.19更新的第三项特性是加入了两大新群系
The next feature added in the 1.19 wild update is the addition of
two new biomes and those biomes are the following.
首先是红树林沼泽
The first biome added is the mangrove swamp which looks like this.
这个群系包含青绿色水域
This biome is composed of teal colored water,
泥块 红树林  以及最重要的青蛙
mud blocks, mangrove trees and most importantly frogs.
第二个新群系是深邃洞穴
The second new biome added in the 1.19 wild update is a biome known as the deep dark.
原计划属于洞穴更新
Originally planned for the cave update,
这个幽暗的洞穴群系仅生成在主世界最深处
the deep dark is a cave biome that's only found near the bottom of the overworld.
这个阴森群系布满幽匿方块  当玩家频繁踩踏时
The scary biome consists of the new skulk blocks that
when walked on enough times will trigger the new mob that I'm sure
会唤醒那个你们早有所闻的新怪物
a lot of you are aware of.
简单介绍完群系后
Now that we've briefly covered the biomes,
接下来要介绍的是在这两个群系中生成的四种新生物
let's talk about the four new mobs that can spawn within them.
野生更新加入的首个新生物  就是青蛙
So the first new mob added in the wild update is the addition of frogs.
青蛙长这样  它们最爱吃小史莱姆  那场面真是令人心碎
Now frogs look like this and love to eat baby slimes and which is just so sad to witness,
我要睡觉了
I'm going to bed.
总之 青蛙拥有五颗心的生命值并分为三种不同变种 温带青蛙
Anyways, frogs have five hearts of health and come in three different
variants which are temperate frogs,
热带青蛙和寒带青蛙
warm frogs and cold frogs.
温带青蛙会自然生成于沼泽群系  而热带青蛙则栖息在红树林沼泽中
Now temperate frogs will spawn naturally in swamp biomes whereas
the warm frogs will spawn naturally in mangrove swamps.
而寒带青蛙则只能由玩家在寒冷群系中繁殖生成  这就引出了我要说的
However, the cold frogs on the other hand can only be spawned by the
player in a cold biome which leads me to talking
新生物  就是蝌蚪
about the next mob that's been added which are tadpoles.
1.19版本还加入了蝌蚪  它们正是青蛙的幼年形态
That's right, tadpoles have also been added in 1.19
which if you didn't know are baby variants of frogs.
蝌蚪无法自然生成  这意味着你只能通过用黏液球喂养两只青蛙来繁殖获得
Now tadpoles cannot spawn naturally which means you can only obtain
them by breeding two frogs with slime balls.
当青蛙进入求爱模式后  它们会在水面上产下蛙卵
Once the frog enters love mode it will lay frog spawn on water.
蛙卵最多需要10分钟孵化  但一旦孵化成功就会生成2到6只蝌蚪
The frog spawn can take up to 10 minutes to hatch
but once they do hatch they'll spawn two to six tadpoles.
这些蝌蚪会在水中漫无目的地游动  还可能被美西螈捕食
The tadpoles will then swim around aimlessly in water and can be hunted and killed by axolotls.
蝌蚪在陆地上同样危险  它们会像鱼一样扑腾挣扎  很快便会脱水而亡
Tadpoles aren't much safer on land either as they'll just flop around like a fish and quickly die as well.
20分钟后 蝌蚪会根据所在群系成长为三种青蛙中的一种
After 20 minutes a tadpole will grow up into one of the three frogs depending on the biome it grows up in.
这意味着要获得寒带青蛙变种  你必须用桶装起蝌蚪然后将其放置在
This means in order to obtain the cold frog variant you will have to pick up a tadpole in a water bucket and place it in
寒冷温度的群系中培育
a biome with a cold temperature.
1.19荒野更新加入的下一个新生物  是2021年生物投票的胜出者  这个可爱的小家伙——悦灵
The next mob added in the 1.19 wild update is the addition of the allay
which is this cute little guy that won the 2021 mob vote.
悦灵是一种被动飞行生物  目前只能在掠夺者前哨站和林地府邸的囚笼中找到
So the allay is a passive flying mob that can only be found
in confined cages at pillager outposts and woodland mansions.
快救救它们 它们被困住了
Someone help them out please they're trapped.
哦等等 我自己能搞定
Oh wait I can do it.
悦灵会漫无目的地游荡  直到玩家对其右键点击  给予它某个物品
Now the allay will just wander around aimlessly until
the player gives it an item by right clicking on them.
悦灵会跟随玩家四处游荡  并寻找与它手持物品相同的掉落物
The allay will then follow the player around trying to find dropped
versions of the same item that it's holding.
比如我给蓝色小家伙一颗钻石  它就会捡起其他掉落的钻石  然后交还给我
For example I could give blue guy a diamond and
they will pick up other dropped diamonds and give them to me which is
说实话这功能相当酷
pretty cool to be honest.
1.19荒野更新加入的第四个  也是最后一个新生物  正是大家期待已久的——监守者
The fourth and final mob added in the 1.19 wild update is a mob
that everyone has been waiting for and that mob is the warden.
监守者是一种敌对生物 它们会出现在我之前提到的新型深暗群系中
So the warden is a hostile mob that looks like this
and can be found in the new deep dark biome I mentioned earlier.
当玩家激活幽匿尖啸体方块时  监守者就会被召唤出来
The warden is summoned when the player activates the new skulk shrieker blocks.
当这个可怕的家伙现身时  你会被施加黑暗效果  这样就能知道监守者要来了
Now you'll know when the warden is coming as you'll be inflicted
with the darkness effect while the scary guy emerges
从地底破土而出
from the ground.
监守者拥有高达250点生命值  这使得它极难被击杀
The warden has a whopping 250 hearts of health making it extremely difficult to kill.
如果你觉得这还不够糟糕  那你就错了  因为在困难模式下监守者能造成惊人的22颗心伤害
If you didn't think it could get worse you're wrong because the warden can deal a
crazy 22 hearts of damage to the player on hard difficulty.
这一击足以秒杀身穿全套下界合金盔甲的玩家  所以务必避开它的近战攻击
This damage is enough to kill the player in one hit while wearing full netherite armor
so you should avoid its melee attack at all costs because you just know why.
监守者是完全失明的  他们只能通过玩家的移动来追踪 所以只要在靠近这些家伙时小心移动你应该不会有太大问题
However it is worth noting that the warden is completely blind meaning they can only
track the player based on their movement so just be careful moving around these guys and you might be okay.
老实说  你多半还是得交代在这儿
Oh let's face it you'll still probably die.
开个玩笑啦 别听我瞎说  我玩我的世界可菜了
Only joking guys don't listen to me I'm trash at Minecraft.
荒野更新中新增了一种光源方块  它就是蛙明灯
A new light source block has been added in the wild update and it's known as the frog light.
蛙明灯共有三种颜色  分别是紫色
So the frog light comes in three different colors which are purple,
绿色和黄色  它们长这样
green and yellow and they look like this.
蛙明灯的亮度等级为15级  当青蛙吞食小型岩浆怪时便会掉落
The frog light emits a light level of 15 and is obtained when a frog eats a tiny magma cube.
这一幕实在太令人心碎了  我还是躺平装死  假装这个特性不存在吧
Again this is so sad to witness so I'm just gonna lie down and pretend this feature doesn't exist.
不过掉落哪种颜色的蛙明灯  取决于击杀岩浆怪的青蛙种类
Anyways the frog light color that's dropped will depend on which frog kills the magma cube.
例如 若由寒带青蛙击杀小型岩浆怪  死亡时便会掉落绿色蛙明灯
For example if a cold frog kills a tiny magma cube it will drop a green frog light upon death.
1.19荒野更新的下一个新特性  是加入了名为“远古城市”的生成建筑
The next feature added in the 1.19 wild update is the addition of
a new generated structure known as the ancient city.
古城可在深邃幽暗的生物群系中找到 主要由深板岩、灵魂火等材质构筑而成
So the ancient city can be found within the deep dark biome and they're
primarily made out of deep slate,soul fire and more.
远古城市中会生成内含独特战利品的宝箱  例如回响碎片
Ancient cities can generate with chests containing lots of new unique loot such as echo shards,
以及新增的“迅捷潜行”附魔书
disc fragments and the new swift sneak enchantment.
还能找到灵魂灯笼
You can also find soul lanterns,
蜡烛  以及骷髅头颅——这是主世界唯一会自然生成的生物头颅  记得一定要捡走这些好东西
candles and skeleton skulls which is the only mob head that can
naturally generate in the overworld so be sure to pick these up.
远古城市宝箱中的珍贵战利品  还可能包含“other side”音乐唱片
Other valuable loot within ancient city chests can include the other side music disc,
钻石护甲  以及附魔金苹果
diamond armor and enchanted golden apples.
1.19荒野更新新增的下一个内容是一张全新的音乐唱片
The next item that's been added in the 1.19 wild update is the addition of a new music disc.
音乐唱片5现已加入我的世界  它与唱片11有着相似的主题风格
That's right music disc 5 has made its way into Minecraft
and it shares a similar theme to music disc 11.
但音乐唱片5的独特之处在于  你无法在自然界直接找到这张唱片本身
However the unique thing about music disc 5 is that you cannot find the disc itself naturally.
玩家需要在远古城市的宝箱中收集散落的唱片碎片
Instead the player must find disc fragments that are scattered about in ancient city chests.
当玩家集齐9个碎片后即可合成音乐唱片5  这将成为游戏中首个可合成的音乐唱片
Once the player finds 9 of the fragments they can craft music disc 5
making this the first craftable music disc in Minecraft.
荒野更新中新增的另一项物品 是一种名为“追溯指针”的全新罗盘
Another new item in the wild update is the addition of a new compass known as the recovery compass.
这个追溯指南针由1个普通指南针与新增的回响碎片合成
So the recovery compass looks like this and is crafted
with one compass and the newly added echo shards that are also found in ancient city chests.
制作完成后  追溯指针会指向你上次死亡的位置  这使它成为找回遗落物品的实用工具 它对我特别有用
Once crafted the recovery compass will point in the direction of where you
previously died making it very useful for finding your lost items aka it's very useful for me.
因为我在我的世界里经常挂掉
Because I die a lot in Minecraft.
我就不该解释这个梗  你们肯定都懂
I don't know why I'm explaining the joke you guys obviously got it.
1.19荒野更新带来了全新的“迅捷潜行”附魔  彻底改变了玩家的移动方式
The 1.19 wild update has changed the way players can move with the new swift sneak enchantment.
没错 如果你有幸在远古城市的宝箱里找到 迅捷潜行附魔书就能给护腿附上这个效果
That's right if you're lucky enough to find a swift sneak book
in an ancient city chest you can add the enchantment to your leggings.
这个附魔能让玩家  在潜行状态下移动得更快
This enchantment allows the player to walk faster while they're sneaking.
这个附魔能让你在躲避监守者时  依然保持快速移动
This is a great enchantment to avoid the warden while still being able to move around quickly.
瞧瞧你这监守者  也没那么吓人嘛 老兄
You know what warden you're not that scary mate look at you.
总之我们继续往下说
Anyways let's move on.
和近年每次更新一样  1.19版本的主界面也焕然一新  呼应荒野更新的主题
As with every update nowadays the Minecraft title screen in 1.19
has been changed to reflect the wild update and I have
不得不说这界面美极了
to say it looks very lovely.
1.19荒野更新中  对树叶进行了改动
In the 1.19 wild update a change has been made to leaves.
所以在1.19版本之前  树叶是不能含水浸没的  这其实很不合理
So prior to 1.19 leaves were not able to be waterlogged which kind of made no sense.
不过在1.19版本中 我放置的所有树叶  现在都能含水浸没了  这是个很贴心的改动
However as of 1.19 you can see that all of the leaves I've
placed are waterlogged which acts as a nice little change
在装饰基地时  这个改动非常实用
when it comes to decorating your base.
1.19版本中  船只又迎来了一项改动  这次是关于它们的材质贴图
Boats have received another change in 1.19 and it's all to do with their textures.
在荒野更新之前  所有类型船只的桨叶颜色都是完全相同的
So prior to the wild update the paddle colors for all the different boat types were the same.
但从1.19版本开始  船桨颜色会对应各自木材的原色  这个细节改动相当用心
However as of 1.19 a change was made to where the boat
paddles now represent their respective wood color which is a nice little change.
在1.19荒野更新前  当盾牌被放入物品展示框时它们的旋转方式非常怪异
Before the 1.19 wild update shields used to spin around
in a very strange way when they were placed in an item frame.
你们看这效果 简直离谱到家了
I mean just look at this man it looks so wrong.
但别担心  1.19版本中盾牌  在展示框里终于能正常旋转了  这又是个贴心的小改动
But don't worry in 1.19 shields actually do spin around properly in
the item frame which is a nice little change once again.
总之各位我是安东尼
Anyways guys my name is Anthony,
希望大家喜欢这次荒野更新
I hope you all enjoyed the wild update.
请尽量不要伤害青蛙  也别被监守者干掉
Try not to kill any frogs please and don't die to the warden.
好的 再见
Okay bye.
我的世界1.20版本现已发布
Minecraft 1.20 is here.
足迹与故事更新带来了全新生物群系
The trails and tails update has added new biomes,
全新生物群落  新增生物种类  独特建筑结构  以及海量惊喜内容
new mobs, new structures and much much more.
今天我将为大家盘点1.20版本新增的100项内容
So today I bring you 100 new things that were added in 1.20.
我的世界为我们带来了全新生物群系
Minecraft has brought us a new biome,
樱花树林
the cherry grove.
这个生物群系较为罕见  但遍布着樱花树
This biome is uncommon but is populated by these cherry blossom trees.
玩家们终于迎来了粉色主题生态群落
Minecraft players finally have their pink biome.
樱花树长这样  和其他树种相比相当独特
The cherry trees look like this and are rather unique compared to other trees.
可以看到树叶周围飘落的小花瓣  这大大提升了环境氛围感
You can see small petals floating around from its leaves which really adds a lot to the atmosphere.
樱花树林还引入了全新原木类型
The cherry grove also brings a new log type.
砍伐这些樱花树  可将其加工成木板以及所有其他木质建材
Chop those cherry trees as they can be crafted down into planks and all the other wood related blocks.
樱花树叶也可像普通树木一样采集  能获得樱花树苗
You can also harvest the leaves like any other tree to obtain the cherry blossom sapling.
我一定要在基地种满樱花树
I'll definitely be planting cherry trees at my base,
我是说谁不想种呢
I mean who wouldn't.
粉色花瓣是一种植物  同样生长在樱花林中  其特性类似海泡菜和蜡烛
Pink petals are a plant that can also be found in the cherry grove and act like sea pickles and candles.
每块泥土类方块上  最多可放置4片粉色花瓣
They can be placed up to 4 in any dirt related block.
看来泥土块现在也变美了
I guess dirt blocks are pretty now,
我是说它们已经够漂亮了
I mean as pretty as they can look.
1.20版本对竹子进行了扩展  现在可以用9根竹子合成竹板材
Bamboo has now been expanded as of 1.20 as you're able to craft bamboo wood from 9 bamboo.
如同樱花木一般
Like the cherry wood,
竹块同样可以加工成  其他木质建材
bamboo blocks can also be crafted down into other wood related blocks.
但竹子与其他木材不同  每份原料只能合成2块竹板  而非通常的4块
However, bamboo is different from other wood types as you're only able to craft 2 planks instead of 4.
这项改动是为了平衡竹子的高获取率  毕竟单次收获就能获得比普通木材多得多的竹子
This change was done to counter bamboo's accessibility as you're able to get a lot
more bamboo from a drop than regular wood from a tree.
考古系统最初在2020年Minecraft Live公布  原计划作为1.17洞穴与山崖更新的内容
Archaeology was originally announced in Minecraft Live 2020 for the 1.17 Caves and Cliffs update.
当时Mojang决定取消这个功能  但在1.20版本中  它带着大量新特性惊艳回归
At the time, Mojang decided to scrap this feature
but in 1.20 it's made an amazing comeback with lots of new features.
沙漠神殿 沙漠水井和海底废墟  现在都新增了考古学相关方块
Desert Temples, Desert Wells and Ocean Ruins were all updated to now contain archaeology related blocks.
考古更新还带来了名为“古迹废墟”的新结构  它们会在针叶林生物群系中生成
The archaeology update also brings a new structure called Trail Ruins which generates in tigers,
雪原针叶林 白桦林和丛林
snowy tigers, birch forests and jungles.
这些遗迹还会生成专属新物品  不过详情我们稍后再谈
These structures also spawn exclusive new items but more on that later.
这些方块看起来有点可疑
Something about these blocks look a little suspicious.
没错 这就是全新的可疑沙砾与可疑沙块
That's right, it's the new Suspicious Sand and Gravel.
可疑沙砾可在沙漠神殿中发现
Suspicious Sand can be found in Desert Temples,
沙漠水井和暖水海洋遗迹中
Desert Wells and Warm Ocean Ruins.
可疑沙砾较为罕见  仅能在冷水海洋遗迹和古迹废墟中找到
Suspicious Gravel is a little rarer only being able to be found in Cold Ocean Ruins and Trail Ruins.
这两种方块都能用新道具刷子进行清理  从而发掘出各种隐藏的方块和物品
Both of these blocks can be brushed away with the new brush tool to discover a variety of blocks and items.
例如 古迹废墟的可疑沙砾  常见战利品表中包含大量随机物品
For example, the common loot table from a Trail Ruins Suspicious Gravel contains so many random items.
我是说 你甚至能找到小麦
I mean, you can find wheat,
煤炭 玻璃板 线
coal, glass panes, string.
这是什么？
What is this?
沙漠神殿的战利品表就友好多了
The Desert Temples loot table is a bit more forgiving.
我是说 你能找到绿宝石这类好东西
I mean, you can find things like emeralds,
钻石 甚至还有TNT炸药
diamonds and even TNT.
正因如此  这两种可疑方块都能让你找到1.20版本新增的稀有物品
With that in mind, both Suspicious Blocks allow you to find rare new items that were added in 1.20.
在这些可疑方块中可以找到的新物品是陶器碎片
The new items that can be found in these Suspicious Blocks are pottery shirts,
千万别和紫水晶碎片搞混了
not to be confused with shards.
在这些可疑方块中
In these Suspicious Blocks,
你可以发现20种不同的陶器碎片图案  其中一些极为稀有  而其他的则较为常见
you can find 20 different pottery shirt designs with some being very rare while others are more common.
例如“举手”图案的陶器碎片  在沙漠水井的可疑沙子中  有25%的生成概率
For example, the Arms Up pottery shirt has a 25% chance of generating inside suspicious sand in a desert well.
“渔夫”图案的陶器碎片
The pottery shirts that are called Angler,
“刀剑” “探险家” “哀悼者”
Blade, Explorer, Mourner,
“丰饶” “庇护所”和“嗅探者”这些图案的陶器碎片  在各自对应的建筑结构中  都有6.7%的生成概率
Plenty, Shelter and Snort all have a 6.7% chance of generating in their respective structure.
这使得这些陶器碎片成为我的世界中最稀有的发现
This makes these pottery shirts the rarest to find in Minecraft,
如果你们找到了的话  记得在评论区告诉我
so let me know in the comments if you find one.
当你收集到足够多的陶器碎片后
Once you have collected enough pottery shirts,
你就可以把它们合成成一种新方块——饰纹陶罐
you'll want to craft them into a new block which are decorated pots.
这些陶罐可以用4块砖合成
These pots can be crafted with 4 bricks,
但它们会是完全素面的
but they will be completely plain,
所以根本没必要这么做
so don't bother doing that.
正确的做法是  用收集到的陶器碎片来定制你的陶罐纹样
Instead, use your collected pottery shirts to craft your pot design,
因为陶罐侧面的纹样会对应你在工作台中使用的碎片图案
as the side textures will correspond to which shirt you use in the crafting table.
例如 你可以在合成陶罐时  在工作台的每个格子里  放入不同的陶器碎片
For example, you could use a different pottery shirt in each section of the
crafting grid for the pot and each side of
这样陶罐的每一面  都会呈现不同的纹样设计
that pot will have a different shirt design.
不过关于陶罐和陶器碎片就说到这里
But enough about pots and pottery shirts,
考古更新中最有趣的掉落物之一  就是嗅探兽的蛋
one of the most interesting items to drop from the archaeology update is the sniffer egg.
嗅探兽蛋只能在温暖海洋遗迹结构中的可疑沙子里找到
The sniffer egg can only be found in suspicious sand within a warm ocean ruin structure.
而且它的生成概率极低  在可疑沙子中仅有6.7%的几率出现
It's also really rare only having a 6.7% chance of generating within the suspicious sand,
那就祝你好运能找到它啦
so have fun finding it.
如果你有幸获得了嗅探兽蛋
If you do manage to obtain a sniffer egg,
记得把它放置下来  因为20分钟后它就会孵化
be sure to place it down as after 20 minutes it will hatch,
孵化出一只超可爱的嗅探兽宝宝
spawning a very cute snifflet.
这就是1.20版本的首个新生物
This introduces our first 1.20 new mob,
这就是嗅探兽  和它的幼崽嗅探兽宝宝
which is the sniffer and the snifflet.
嗅探兽无法自然生成  只能通过嗅探兽蛋孵化出幼崽
Sniffers cannot spawn naturally and are only hatched as snifflets from sniffer eggs.
嗅探兽宝宝最终会成长为成年嗅探兽  成年后拥有7颗心的生命值  虽然拥有六条腿却行动迟缓
Snifflets will eventually grow up into sniffers which will have 7 hearts
of health and are very slow creatures despite having 6 legs.
嗅探兽的主要功能是通过嗅探挖掘出独有的特殊植物种子
The main purpose of the sniffer is to sniff out and dig up exclusive unique plant seeds.
嗅探兽会挖掘出两种装饰性植物
Sniffers will dig up two decorative plants,
火把花  和瓶子草
the torchflower and the pitcher plant.
火把花种子非常实用  可以用来繁殖嗅探兽
Torchflower seeds are useful as they can be used to breed sniffers,
鸡  和鹦鹉
chickens, and parrots.
种植火把花种子后
When torchflower seeds are planted,
会经历四个（更正：三个）生长阶段  成熟后的火把花可用于制作橙色染料
they grow in four different stages and the fully grown torchflower can be used to craft orange dye.
唯一让我困惑的是  为什么火把花不会发光
The only thing that confuses me is why the torchflower doesn't emit light.
说实话  我觉得这是个被错过的亮点
I mean, I think that was a missed opportunity to be honest.
嗅探兽还能找到  瓶子草荚果  它有五个生长阶段
Pitcher pods are also found by sniffers and have five different growing stages.
当瓶子草荚果  完全长成瓶子草后
Once the pitcher pod fully grows into a pitcher plant,
可用于制作青色染料
it can be used to craft cyan dye.
瓶子草荚果在基岩版更实用  既能用来繁殖鸡  也能驯服鹦鹉
The pitcher pod is even more useful in bedrock edition
as it can be used to breed chickens and tame parrots.
1.20版本最具争议的改动  是下界合金升级的锻造台机制
A somewhat controversial feature in 1.20 is the update made
made to the smithing table for netherite upgrades.
在1.20中要将装备升级为下界合金
To upgrade your armor and tools to netherite in 1.20,
必须使用锻造模板
you need the smithing template,
这种模板只能在下界堡垒中找到
which can only be found in bastion structures within the nether.
你也可以用七颗钻石和一块下界岩  复制下界合金升级模板
You can also duplicate the netherite upgrade smithing template by
by using seven diamonds and one netherrack.
在1.20版本升级下界合金  难度确实提高了
It's definitely going to be harder to upgrade your netherite in 1.20,
但我觉得这个改动不错  这让下界合金更具价值
but I think it's a good change because it makes netherites more valuable.
现在来到公认的  Minecraft 1.20最棒内容
Now we come to what's considered the best part of Minecraft 1.20,
盔甲纹饰
armor trims.
盔甲纹饰是可应用于装备的独特图案
Armor trims are unique patterns that can be applied to your armor.
游戏新增了16种独特盔甲纹饰  每种纹饰只能在特定建筑结构中获取
There are 16 different armor trims added
with each trim only being able to be found within their own unique structure.
这些盔甲纹饰可与锭块和晶体组合  创造出超过616种不同的盔甲装饰方案
These armor trims can be used in combination with
ingots and crystals to make over 616 different armor trim combinations.
可以说玩家们将会为盔甲打造出各式各样的纹饰设计
So it's safe to say players are going to make lots of different armor trim designs for their armor.
现在简单说说如何在各个独特建筑中找到每种盔甲纹饰
Now let's briefly talk about how you can find each armor trim within their own unique structure.
盔甲纹饰的名称会提示它们的获取地点
So the names of the armor trims give you a hint as to where you can find them.
例如“眼眸纹饰”可在要塞中获得  有10%几率生成于祭坛箱内  而末地城中的箱子里必定会出现
For example, the eye armor trim is found in a stronghold
with a 10% chance of spawning in an altar chest and a 100%
100%几率出现在要塞图书馆的箱子中
chance of spawning in a library chest.
最难获取的盔甲纹饰当属监守纹饰与幽静纹饰
The most difficult armor trim to obtain are the ward and silence armor trims.
这两种纹饰均可在远古城市箱中找到  守卫纹饰生成概率为5%  而幽静纹饰仅有1.2%的生成概率
Both trims can be found in ancient city chests with the ward trim having a 5%
chance of spawning while the silence trim only has a 1.2% chance of spawning.
这使得幽静纹饰成为最稀有的盔甲装饰  当然它只生成于最危险的建筑之中 这使得获取难度更加艰巨
This makes the silence armor trim the rarest
armor trim to find and of course it spawns in the most dangerous structure making it even harder to get.
我的世界中最独特的盔甲纹饰当属“潮汐纹饰”  因为它只能由远古守卫者掉落  且掉落概率仅有20%
The most unique armor trim in Minecraft is the tide as it can
only be dropped by an elder guardian with a 20% chance.
Mojang终于给了玩家们探索海底神殿  挑战远古守卫者的理由  因为这个盔甲纹饰确实帅爆了
Mojang have finally given players a reason to seek out ocean
monuments and face elder guardians because this armor trim is pretty cool.
你喜欢和朋友们一起在我的世界里旅行探险吗？
Do you enjoy traveling in your Minecraft world with your friends?
那么我很荣幸地向大家介绍1.20版本第二个全新生物——骆驼
Well I proudly present to you all 1.20's second newest mod which is the camel.
骆驼是最理想的旅行伙伴  它们能同时承载两名玩家  而且与马匹不同  骆驼无需驯服即可骑乘
The camel is the perfect companion for you to use as they can take up
to 2 players and unlike a horse camels don't actually need to be tamed.
不过骑乘骆驼需要配备鞍具  所以务必提前准备好鞍座
You will however need a saddle to ride them so make sure you have one of those on hand.
骆驼会自然生成于沙漠生物群系  拥有16颗心的生命值  堪称生物界的重装坦克
Camels will naturally spawn in desert biomes and they have 16
hearts of health so they're quite the tanky mob.
手持仙人掌时骆驼会跟随玩家 这意味着你可以用它来繁殖骆驼
Camels will also follow players around if they are holding
cacti which means you can use it to breed them.
骆驼的体型也相当高大
Camels are also quite tall,
高大到任何两格高或更矮的生物  都无法攻击到骑在骆驼上的玩家
so tall that any mob that is 2 blocks tall or shorter will not
be able to reach the players riding the camels.
不过蜘蛛是个例外  它们能直接攀爬上来攻击你
Spiders however are an exception as they'll still be able to reach you by just climbing,
所以千万要当心
so be careful.
尽管骆驼拥有冲刺能力  和跨越障碍的优势
While camels have their advantages like being able to dash or walk over obstacles,
但它们也存在一些劣势
they do have some disadvantages.
首先 骆驼天性比较懒惰
The first is that camels are kind of lazy.
它们会突然原地坐下  再想让它们起身可不容易
They will randomly just sit down and it's difficult to get them to move again.
骆驼的速度也并不算快
Camels aren't particularly fast either,
即便全速奔跑时  它们的速度也超不过驴子
I mean even at max running speed they're no faster than a donkey.
你喜欢我的世界的背景音乐吗？
Oh, are you a fan of Minecraft music?
那你一定会爱上接下来的新功能
Then you'll love this next feature.
这是因为在1.20版本中  Mojang新增了一张音乐唱片
This is because in 1.20 Mojang has added another music disc.
这张唱片名为“遗迹”  充满复古怀旧风格
The music disc is called Relic and it's very retro.
该唱片仅可在“试炼遗迹”结构中获取  生成于可疑沙砾时有8.3%的几率出现
This music disc can only be obtained in a trail ruin structure
with an 8.3% chance of it being generated in suspicious gravel.
1.20版本新增了一个生物头颅  现在你可以获得猪灵的头颅了
There's a new mob head on the block in 1.20 as you can now obtain piglin heads.
当猪灵被闪电苦力怕炸死时  你就能获得它的头颅
That's you're able to obtain a piglin head if a piglin dies to a charged creeper.
不过我得提醒  把闪电苦力怕弄到下界可不容易
I will say though, it's going to be a challenge getting a charged creeper into the nether.
猪灵头颅被玩家佩戴或接收到红石信号时  耳朵会扇动
Piglin heads will also flap their ears when it's worn by the player or if it is powered by redstone.
佩戴猪灵头颅还能将猪灵的侦测范围降低50%
Wearing the piglin head will also reduce the detection range of a piglin by 50%.
长期以来  标记基地和位置  只能用普通告示牌
For the longest time the only way you could label your bases and locations was with regular old signs.
但从1.20版本开始  游戏新增了悬挂式告示牌
But as of 1.20 Minecraft has added hanging signs.
这种告示牌可贴墙悬挂  也能从方块下方垂吊
Hanging signs can be placed against walls or hang from blocks.
还支持多层悬挂  为建筑党提供了新玩具
They can also hang on top of each other which gives builders a new toy to play with.
悬挂告示牌的额外福利是  现在普通告示牌也能双面书写了
A bonus feature alongside hanging signs is the ability to write on both sides of regular signs.
不仅如此  如果写错了字  只需右键点击就能修改
Not only that but if you make a mistake you can now edit signs by simply right clicking on them.
这个功能我等得实在太久了
I can't even begin to tell you how long I've waited for this feature,
真是等得太久了
it's been so long.
1.20版本新增的錾制书架方块  终于能打造真正的图书馆了
Real libraries are now possible with the new chisel bookshelf block that's been added in the 1.20 update.
这些新书架由  6块木板和3个木台阶合成  每个书架最多可存放6本书
These new bookshelves are crafted with six planks and three wooden slabs and each bookshelf can store up to six books.
这包括附魔书在内
This includes enchanted books,
书与笔  以及成书
written books and book and quills.
Mojang为游戏新增了全新的竹筏船类型
Mojang have added a brand new boat type into Minecraft which is called the raft.
竹筏由竹子制成  功能与普通船只完全相同  还配备了带储物箱的变体
The raft is made out of bamboo and functions exactly
the same as a regular boat and also has a chest variant.
竹筏与普通船只的唯一区别在于  玩家坐在竹筏上的位置略高于普通船
The only difference with rafts to boats is that players sit slightly higher in a raft than they do in a boat.
Minecraft在1.20版本新增了四首原声音乐  让游戏氛围更加丰富多彩
Minecraft has really started to jazz things up in 1.20 by adding four new soundtracks.
第一首曲目名为Familiar Room  会在所有生物群系中播放
The first track is called Familiar Room and it plays in all biomes.
第二首曲目名为Bromeliad
The second track is called Bromeliad,
希望我没念错
I hope I'm saying that right,
并在竹林生物群系中播放
and it plays in bamboo jungles,
樱花林  繁花森林  以及丛林生物群系中播放
cherry groves, flower forests and jungle biomes.
第三首曲目名为Crescent Dunes  在沙漠及所有恶地类生物群系中播放
The third track is called Crescent Dunes which plays in deserts and all types of badland biomes.
最后一首Echo in the Winds  专为樱花林场景谱写
And finally we have Echo in the Winds which plays in cherry groves,
繁茂洞穴  繁花森林  以及所有恶地类生物群系中播放
lush caves, flower forests and all type of badland biomes.
值得一提的是  这四首全新曲目  都会在主菜单界面播放
It's worth noting that all four of these new songs will all play on the menu screen.
说到主菜单界面
Speaking of the menu screen,
1.20版本更新了标题界面  背景已替换为樱花林生物群系景观
the title screen received an update in 1.20 as it now features a cherry grove biome in the background.
我超爱樱花林群系的兄弟
I love the cherry grove biome man,
这绝对是我的新宠之一
it's probably one of my new favourites.
1.20版本还新增了五条主菜单标语  分别是 沙子很可疑
1.20 has also added five new menu splashes and those splashes are The Sand is Sus,
记得要刷……牙
Remember to Brush Your... Teeth,
拥有可工作的书架
Has Working Bookshelves,
“嗅嗅”  以及“此处应放悬挂式告示牌”
Sniff Sniff, and Place Hanging Sign Here.
1.20版本还带来了一些贴心的细节优化  首先现在你可以对地毯 羊毛和床  重新染成任意其他颜色
1.20 has also introduced some really nice quality of life changes with the
first being that you can now re-dye carpet,wool and beds to any other colour.
另一项改动是无需潜行也能将生物头颅直接放置在音符盒上了
Another change is that mob heads can now be placed on noteblocks without sneaking,
这一改动非常便利  再也不用担心误触音符盒了
which is a very convenient change for not accidentally triggering the noteblock.
1.20版本对生物头颅做了超酷的改动  把头颅放在音符盒上时  会播放该生物对应的
In 1.20 a really cool change has been made to mob heads where if you
place them on noteblocks it will now play the
该生物的环境音效  （当红石激活时）
ambient sound of that mob when it is powered by redstone.
这下你可以对朋友玩些超损的恶作剧了  比如突然播放苦力怕的嘶嘶声
This is gonna allow you to play some really horrible pranks on your
friends as you can just play some creeper sounds
在他们附近播放  绝对能把人吓得够呛
near them and they'll just be terrified.
如果你觉得史莱姆和岩浆怪跳得不够高  那么1.20的改动一定会让你满意  现在史莱姆
If you thought slimes and magma cubes couldn't jump high enough
then you're going to like the change in 1.20 as slimes
和岩浆怪现在会受到跳跃提升效果的影响了
and magma cubes are now affected by the jump boost effect.
老实说 看着史莱姆跳这么高还真有点瘆人
Okay I can't lie, watching this slime jump really high is actually kinda scary.
在1.20版本之前有个设计真的让我特别抓狂
Before 1.20 there was something that really pushed my buttons.
在1.20之前磨制黑石按钮的破坏时间 比其他按钮要长得多这简直... 图啥呢？
So basically before 1.20 polished blackstone buttons
took longer to break than other buttons which was just... why?
不过好在1.20修复了这个bug  现在所有按钮的破坏时间都统一了
But yeah, in 1.20 this bug was fixed as all buttons take the same time to break.
视频最后分享几个1.20冷知识  首先是樱花林群系原本计划
Here are some 1.20 facts to end off the video
with the first being that the cherry grove biome was originally planned to
在2013年就计划加入
be added by Mojang in 2013.
没错 樱花林群系足足等了十年才实装
That's right, it took 10 years for the cherry blossom biome to be added.
迟到总比不到好
Better late than never I guess.
最后 用一个小知识结束本期视频
And finally, a fact to end off the video,
1.20足迹与故事更新  正好是在1.19荒野更新发布一年后推出的
the 1.20 trails and tails update has been released exactly one year after the 1.19 wild update.
不过以上就是1.20“足迹与故事”更新的全部新增内容了
But anyways that just about wraps up all the features that have been added
in the 1.20 trails and tails update.
以下是我的世界1.21和1.20.5版本中新增的29项内容
Here are 29 things to be added in Minecraft 1.21 and 1.20.5.
我的世界1.21版本将加入新生物
Minecraft 1.21 is getting a new mob,
沼骸
the Bogged.
沼骸是骷髅的变种  全身覆盖着苔藓和蘑菇
The Bogged is a variant of skeleton that's covered in moss and mushrooms.
沼骸仅有8颗心生命值  比普通骷髅的10颗心少了2颗心
The Bogged only has 8 hearts of health which is 2 hearts
less than a regular skeleton having 10 hearts.
这些家伙会生成在沼泽和红树林沼泽中  行为模式与骷髅相似  只是攻击速度较慢但射程更远
These guys can spawn in swamp and manga of swamps and behave similar to
skeletons except they attack slower but shoot
会射出剧毒之箭
tipped arrows of poison.
换句话说  我的世界新增了会射毒箭的骷髅  这玩意儿绝对烦人得要命
In other words, Minecraft has added a skeleton that shoots
poison arrows which is going to be really annoying.
正如你们中有些人可能知道的
As some of you may know,
我的世界1.21版本还将新增一个名为“试炼大厅”的全新结构
Minecraft 1.21 is also adding a new structure which is called the Trial Chamber.
试炼大厅将生成在主世界由多种铜质方块构成
The Trial Chamber will generate in the overworld and it's made out of a variety of copper blocks.
这个结构的目的是为玩家提供战斗挑战
The purpose of this structure is to provide a combat challenge for players,
当你探索这个结构时
as when you explore the structure,
你会遇到装有新型刷怪笼的房间  这种刷怪笼被称为“试炼刷怪笼”
you encounter rooms that contain a new spawner variant that is called the Trial Spawner.
刷怪笼旁包围的方块则暗示了该刷怪笼可能生成的生物类型
Trial spawners look like this and the blocks that surround the spawner
act as a hint as to which mob can spawn from said spawner.
例如 若刷怪笼被蜘蛛网环绕
For example, if the spawner is surrounded by cobwebs,
它就会生成蜘蛛
it will spawn spiders.
如果周围是骨块环绕
If it's surrounded by bone blocks,
就会生成骷髅
it will spawn skeletons.
另一种必定生成的试炼刷怪笼会生成名为“旋风人”的新生物
Another type of trial spawner that will always generate
is a spawner that spawns a new mob that is called the Breeze.
它是一种敌对生物会通过发射风弹来攻击玩家
The Breeze looks like this and is a hostile mob that attacks by firing wind charges at the player.
这种攻击若命中你  会造成极强的击退效果  相当令人头疼
This attack will deal high knockback to you if you're hit by it which can be kind of annoying.
轻风拥有15颗心的生命值  若你成功击杀它
The Breeze has 15 hearts of health and if you manage to kill it,
会掉落名为“旋风棒”的物品
it will drop Breeze Rods which look like this.
这些轻风之杖可用于合成  新增的武器——重锤
These Breeze Rods can be used to craft a new weapon that's been added and it's called the Mace,
不过这个我们稍后再详谈
but more on that later.
试炼刷怪笼的运作机制  与普通刷怪笼不同  它会以波次形式生成怪物而非持续刷新
Now these trial spawners work differently to normal spawners as
the mobs that spawn from them will spawn in waves instead of spawning constantly.
当击败所有生成的怪物后
Once the mobs are defeated,
试炼刷怪笼会进入  30分钟的冷却状态  同时你的努力也会获得回报
the trial spawner will go into cooldown mode for 30 minutes but you'll also be rewarded for your efforts.
没错 刷怪笼会弹出随机宝藏物品以及一种新道具——试炼钥匙
That's right, the spawner will eject random treasure items as well as a new item called the Trial Key.
试炼钥匙用于开启可在试炼密室中找到的特殊宝箱
The Trial Key is used to unlock a type of chest that can be found in the Trial Chamber.
这些被称为“宝库”  使用钥匙解锁后
These are called Vaults and once you unlock the key,
就能获得各种特殊物品  包括一种新道具——沉重核心
you can get a variety of special items including a new item called the Heavy Core.
将沉重核心与我刚才提到的旋风棒结合 便能合成Minecraft最新武器——重锤
Now the Heavy Core when combined with the Breeze Rod I mentioned earlier
allows you to create Minecraft's newest weapon which is called the Mace.
重锤是一种重型武器  基础伤害为3.5颗心  暴击时可达5.25颗心
The Mace is a heavy weapon that does a base damage of 3.5 hearts or 5.25 hearts with a critical hit.
然而重锤真正强大到逆天之处在于其伤害值会随坠落高度增加
However, what makes the Mace so awesome and overpowered is
that it's damage increases depending on how high you fall when you attack with it.
这意味着我从3格高跳下就能一击秒杀这只苦力怕
This means I can fall from like 3 blocks high and kill this creeper in one hit.
但重锤更疯狂的地方在于它的坠落伤害加成没有上限
But what's even crazier about the Mace is that the amount of damage it can inflict when falling is unlimited.
这意味着从97格高空坠落时  你甚至能秒杀监守者 简直离谱到极点
This means you could literally kill the Warden when falling from 97 blocks high and yeah that's just insane.
但重锤最酷的地方在于  如果你能在坠落时成功命中
But the coolest thing about the Mace is that if you manage to land a successful hit when falling,
你就能完全抵消原本会承受的坠落伤害
you will negate any of the fall damage that you were meant to take.
这武器简直强到离谱啊
This weapon is seriously overpowered man.
狼自2011年加入游戏以来  基本没有太大变化
Wolves have remained mostly unchanged since they were added in 2011.
但在1.20.5的最新快照中
But in a recent snapshot for 1.20.5,
狼群迎来了一项重大变革
Wolves have received a huge change.
我的世界现在推出了8种新狼变种  它们会生成在特定的生物群系中
That's right, Minecraft is introducing 8 new variations of
the Wolf that can now be found in their specific biome.
我们熟悉的2011年经典狼种  依然会保留在游戏中
Now the original Wolf we know and love from 2011 isn't going anywhere,
原版狼只是更名为“苍狼”  现在仅会出现在针叶林生物群系
it's just instead being renamed to the Pale Wolf and can now only be found in Tiger Biomes.
话虽如此  新增的第一款狼皮肤就是这种斑点狼
With that said, our first new Wolf skin that was added is known as the Spotted Wolf which looks like this.
这种狼变种可在热带草原高原生物群系中发现其外观 与我们12年来熟知的狼截然不同 以至于我一时难以适应看到它
This Wolf variant can be found in the Savannah Plateau Biome and it looks drastically different to the Wolf
we've had for over 12 years so I'm not used to seeing this.
接下来是条纹狼 生成于繁茂的恶地生物群系
Next up we have the Striped Wolf which looks like this and is found in the Wooded Badlands Biome.
我们还迎来了雪原狼  它出没于雪林生物群系 以及可在雪原针叶林发现的灰狼
We have also been blessed with the Snowy Wolf which can be found in the
Grove Biome as well as the Ashen Wolf which can be found in the Snowy Tiger.
接着是栗色狼  它只会在原始云杉针叶林生物群系中生成
We then have the Chestnut Wolf which can only be found in the Old Growth variant of the Spruce Tiger Biome.
判断是否为原始针叶林生物群系而非普通针叶林 的关键在于观察云杉树异常高大
The way you know you've found an Old Growth Tiger Biome
instead of a regular one is if some of the spruce trees are huge.
接下来是黑狼  它出没于原始松木针叶林生物群系  注意不要与之前提到的原始云杉林生物群系相混淆
We then have the Black Wolf which is located in an Old Growth Pine Tiger Biome
which is not to be confused with the Old Growth Spruce Biome I mentioned before.
赭红狼栖息于丛林生物群系
We have the Rusty Wolf which is located in the Jungle Biome and looks like this.
最后登场的是我个人最爱的变种  森林狼
And finally we have my personal favourite which is the Woods variant of the Wolf.
这些家伙出没于森林生物群系  很可能成为我驯服的第一匹狼  因为我实在太爱这个变种了
These guys can be found in Forest Biomes and it will probably be the
first Wolf I tame because I just absolutely love how they look.
不过虽然狼的行为模式保持不变
Now while the Wolf behaviour will remain the same,
玩家现在更有理由探索主世界了  因为可以收集所有不同品种的狼 而不是驯养八匹  长得一模一样的狼
players have been given more of a reason to explore the overworld now as you can collect all the different
Wolf variants across the world instead of having 8 Wolves that just look identical.
不过说真的
Although let's be real,
我八成还是会这么干  毕竟原版狼永远是最经典的
I'll still probably do that because the OG Wolf will always be the best.
不过话说回来  你最喜欢新增的哪个狼品种呢？
But yeah, what is your favourite Wolf variant that's been added?
在评论区告诉我吧
Let me know in the comments.
不仅我的世界即将迎来新的狼种
Not only do we have new Wolves coming to Minecraft,
同时游戏还将新增狼铠  为我们最好的伙伴提供额外防护
we also have Wolf Armor being added to give our best friends some extra protection.
狼铠需要用犰狳鳞甲制作 而鳞甲可以通过
So Wolf Armor is crafted with Armadillo Scutes which can be obtained from,
从犰狳身上获取  具体细节我们稍后再详谈
well, Armadillos but more on that later.
狼铠拥有64点耐久度  能完全吸收其他生物造成的伤害
The Wolf Armor has 64 durability points and absorbs all damage from other mobs,
来自玩家和环境的伤害  则会完全穿透护甲
the player and full damage.
不过话虽如此
However, with that said,
狼铠无法吸收  溺水时狼受到的伤害
Wolf Armor will not absorb damage dealt to the Wolf if they are drowning,
冻伤或窒息造成的伤害
freezing or suffocating.
你可以手持剪刀右键点击狼  来卸下它们身上的护甲  还能在工作台中
Wolf Armor can be unequipped from your Wolf by
right clicking them with shears and you can also dye your Wolf Armor by
将护甲与染料合成  来改变狼铠颜色
combining it with dye in the crafting grid.
我的世界1.20.5版本新增了犰狳生物
A new mob was added for Minecraft 1.20.5 which is the Armadillo.
犰狳属于被动型生物  通常生成于恶地与热带草原群系
Armadillos are passive mobs and can be found in Badlands and Savannah biomes.
这种生物非常胆小
Armadillos are easily scared,
受到伤害或靠近亡灵生物时  会立即蜷缩成球状
rolling up into a ball if they're hurt or if they're standing close to undead mobs.
玩家在附近疾跑时也会触发这个反应
They'll also do this if the player is sprinting near them,
蜷缩状态下的犰狳会获得减伤效果  这对仅有6颗心生命值的它们非常实用
but when Armadillos are rolled up they'll take less damage
which is handy for them as they only have 6 hearts of health.
犰狳会掉落鳞甲
Armadillos will drop Scutes,
这正是我之前提到的制作狼铠所需的材料
which is the item I mentioned earlier to craft Wolf Armor.
获取犰狳鳞甲有两种方式
There are two ways to get Armadillo Scutes.
一是用刷子清洁犰狳  二是等待5-10分钟  犰狳会自行脱落鳞甲
One way is by using a brush on an Armadillo or you can just
wait 5-10 minutes for an Armadillo to drop a Scute.
我的世界1.21.4版本现已上线
Minecraft 1.21.4 is here.
或者说1.22？
Or is it 1.22?
“花园觉醒”更新带来了全新生物群系
The Garden Awakens update has added new biomes,
新增生物 方块  以及海量内容
new mobs, new blocks and much much more.
今天我将为大家展示本次更新的全部新增要素
So today I'll be showing you all of the new things that were added in this update.
游戏新增了一个
Minecraft has added a new,
阴森诡谲的神秘群系名为“苍白之园”
scary and mysterious biome and it is known as the Pale Garden.
苍白之园是黑森林的变种群系  踏入其中便会发现  这里遍布着苍白橡树这一全新树种
The Pale Garden biome is a variant of the Dark Forest and upon entering the
biome you'll notice it's filled with a new tree type known as the Pale Oak Tree.
但更引人注目的是  这片区域异常荒芜  几乎寸草不生
But what you'll probably notice more is how empty and barren it is.
这是因为白天时  被动型生物无法在此自然生成
This is because no passive mobs can spawn here during the day.
但让苍白之园更显荒凉的  是探索时萦绕耳畔的寂静环境音效
But what makes the Pale Garden feel even more empty is
the quiet ambient sounds that are present when exploring the biome.
苍白之园的独特之处在于  尽管白昼时看似宁静祥和
However, the Pale Garden is unique because despite the biome being rather peaceful during the day,
夜幕降临后  这里便会化作令人毛骨悚然的恐怖之地
it becomes a much more creepy and scary place to be when nightfall hits.
当你在夜晚探索苍白之园时   会听到群系中回荡着各种诡异声响
So when exploring the Pale Garden at night you will hear many strange sounds within the biome,
但最令人毛骨悚然的  是那些苍白橡树发出的声响
but more specifically the trees.
不仅苍白之园本身会传来诡异声响
Not only will you hear creepy sounds in the Pale Garden itself,
你还可能在树丛间偶遇一种栖息于此的全新生物
you may also stumble across a new mob that is found within the trees.
想必有些观众已经认出这种生物
Now this mob, as some of you may know,
这种生物  名为嘎枝
is called the Creaking.
嘎枝怪是一种敌对生物  外形与苍白之园中的树木极为相似
The Creaking is a hostile mob that closely resembles the trees that are found within the Pale Garden.
嘎枝怪仅在夜间出没  当玩家进入其12格范围内时便会惊动它们
The Creaking can only be found at night time and is alerted to the player if you are within 12 blocks of them.
有趣的是  嘎枝怪的攻击方式与游戏中其他生物截然不同
Now what's interesting is that the Creaking's method of attack is very unique from other mobs in the game.
若你直视嘎枝怪
So if you are looking directly at the Creaking,
它会以极其诡异的姿态静止不动  完全不攻击玩家
it will stand still in a very strange fashion and not attack the player.
但只要你一转身背对它们
But the second you turn away from them,
它们便会疾速追来  以近战攻击猛击你
they will sprint after you and begin to hit you with a melee attack.
嘎枝怪的攻击在简单模式下  会造成半颗心的伤害
The Creaking's attack will deal 1 heart of damage on easy mode,
普通模式下造成1.5颗心伤害  困难模式则会造成2颗心伤害
1.5 on normal and 2 hearts on hard.
若想让吱嘎怪停止攻击
Now if you want the Creaking to stop attacking,
只需再次注视它们  嘎枝怪便会恢复雕像般的静止状态
just simply look at them again and they will return to their statue-like position.
但如果你想杀死嘎枝怪
However, if you want to kill the Creaking,
它的击杀方式与其他生物截然不同
it must be killed differently from other mobs.
你不能简单地用剑砍它或是用弓箭射杀它
You see, you can't just hit it with a sword or shoot it with a bow.
你必须找到它的生命之源  并将其摧毁
You instead have to locate its health source and destroy it.
你需要找到一种名为“嘎枝之心”的新方块
This can be done by finding a new block that is known as the Creaking Heart.
直接击打嘎枝怪  会使它们散发出粒子效果
So punching the Creaking directly will cause them to emit particles.
跟随这些粒子  它们会指引你找到苍白之园中的某棵树
Follow these particles and they will lead you to a nearby tree found within the Pale Garden.
当你摧毁粒子指向的树干时
If you then destroy the tree logs that the particles lead to,
就会发现隐藏其中的嘎枝之心方块
you will stumble across the Creaking Heart block.
只需破坏嘎枝之心  嘎枝怪便会立即消失死亡
Simply break and destroy the Creaking Heart and the Creaking itself will disappear and die.
有趣的是  使用精准采集附魔工具  可以完整采集嘎枝之心
What's interesting about the Creaking Heart is that you can mine it
with a Silk Touch enchanted tool and keep the block.
这样你就能在世界的任何地方重新召唤嘎枝怪
This allows you to spawn the Creaking mob wherever you are in your Minecraft world.
前提是将嘎枝之心  放置在两根苍白橡木之间
That's providing the Creaking Heart is placed between two Pale Oak Logs.
这就引出了花园觉醒更新的  下一个新增内容
This brings me to the next addition in the Garden Awakens update.
游戏中新增了一种树木  名为苍白橡树
So a new tree type has been added to the game and they're known as the Pale Oak Trees.
这些造型独特的树木 自然生成于苍白之园生物群系中
These trees are uniquely shaped looking like this and are of course found within the Pale Garden Biome.
这样你就能获得一种名为苍白橡木的新木材
This allows you to obtain a new wood type which is known as the Pale Oak Logs.
如同游戏中的其他木材一样
Like every other wood type in the game,
苍白橡木可加工成木板  进而制作所有苍白橡木制品
The Pale Oak Logs can be crafted into planks which can then be used to craft into all of the Pale Oak Logs.
相信建筑玩家们一定会为这种新木材兴奋不已
I think builders in particular are going to be very excited to build with this new wood type,
这木材看起来太棒了
I mean it looks awesome.
花园觉醒更新中新增的另一种方块  是树脂
Another new block that's been introduced into the Garden Awakens update is the addition of Resin.
当你在苍白之园生物群系探索时  可能会注意到某些苍白橡树上  挂着这种奇特的橙色树脂滴
So when you are exploring the Pale Garden Biome
you may notice that some of the Pale Oak Trees have these weird orange dots on them.
这些橙色物质就是树脂  它们只会出现在内部藏有嘎枝树心的苍白橡树上
These orange pieces are known as Resin and can only be found on
Pale Oak Trees that have a Creaking Heart inside of it.
树脂可直接用手采集  或通过击碎嘎枝树心方块掉落
Resin can be obtained and collected with your hand or can be dropped by the Creaking Heart block itself.
获取树脂块后可像这样装饰任意方块或建筑
Resin Clumps when obtained can be used to decorate any block or Minecraft build looking like this.
但更重要的是
But more importantly,
树脂块能在熔炉中烧炼  产出树脂砖
the Resin Clumps can be used to smelt in a Furnace giving the player Resin Bricks.
树脂砖可合成脂砖方块
Resin Bricks can be used to craft into the block form of Resin Brick looking like this.
继而加工成树脂砖台阶
You can then use the Resin Brick blocks to craft them into Resin Brick Slabs,
树脂砖楼梯  树脂砖墙  以及錾制树脂砖
Resin Brick Stairs, Resin Brick Walls and finally Chiseled Resin Bricks.
这些方块都极具特色  而我尤其钟爱錾制树脂砖  细看会发现砖面上刻着嘎枝怪物的图腾
These are all really cool looking but I especially love the Chiseled Resin Brick
as if you look closely you'll notice the symbol of a Creaking Mob on it.
这或许将成为我最爱的装饰方块
This might be my new favourite decorative block.
树脂还有个妙用  能为盔甲染上独特色泽
Another really cool thing you can do with the Resin is dye your armour with it.
只需使用锻造台放入盔甲
Just simply use a Smithing Table and place your armour,
一件盔甲纹饰  外加一块树脂砖  你的盔甲瞬间焕发独特光彩
an Armour Trim and a Resin Brick and BAM your armour stands out even more.
苍白之园生态域  还藏着更多秘密等待发掘
The Pale Garden Biome still has other things to be found.
其中包括新增的  名为“眼眸花”的奇异植物
This includes the addition of a new flower which is called the Eye Blossom.
眼眸花是种会随昼夜更替  变换形态的奇异花卉
The Eye Blossom is a unique flower that changes its state depending on the day and night cycle.
白昼时分花朵紧闭  夜幕降临后便会绽放显露出中央的眼瞳“眼眸花”由此得名
During the day the flower is closed but when it turns to night it
opens up and reveals its eye hence the name Eye Blossom.
当花朵绽放时会发出独特声响  并与三格范围内的其他眼眸花产生共鸣
The flower will also make a unique sound when it opens and
will communicate with other Eye Blossom flowers within a 3 block radius.
这种共鸣表现为  当三格范围内存在其他眼眸花时它们会随机同步开合
What I mean by this is that the flowers will randomly
open and close when they're next to each other in a 3 block radius
这确实有点...呃...毛骨悚然
which is uh pretty creepy actually.
当白昼再度降临时眼眸花会重新恢复闭合状态
It's also worth noting that the Eye Blossom flower will
return back to their closed state when it turns back to daytime.
关于眼眸花有个悲伤的事实  若将其喂食给蜜蜂这些蜜蜂会
A sad but true feature about the Eye Blossom is
that if you try to feed them to bees then the bees actually become
中毒而亡
poisoned.
看着真让人难受啊兄弟
This is just awful to watch man.
我们继续吧
Let's move on.
苍白之园的另一独特之处在于  水体颜色会随环境改变  与整个生态完美融合
Another unique feature about the Pale Garden Biome is that the colour of
the water has been changed to match it.
这意味着苍白之园生态群系中  所有水源方块都会呈现这种灰蒙蒙的色调
This means any water source block you see within the Pale Garden
Biome will have a greyish tone to it looking like this.
你会喝这水吗
Would you drink this water?
我可不喝
I don't think I would.
苍白之园里  还有我先前漏说的另一种方块
The Pale Garden is also home to another block that I missed.
现在要说的这个方块  就是苍白垂须
Now the block I'm talking about is the Pale Hanging Moss which looks like this.
有趣的是  当苍白苔藓附着在苍白橡木原木或树叶上时会发出环境音效
What's interesting is if the Pale Moss is attached to Pale Oak Logs or Leaves then it will emit ambient sounds.
现在来聊聊1.21.4版本的改动
Now let's talk about some of the changes that were made in 1.21.4.
首项改动是标题界面  和每次我的世界更新一样  这次换上了苍白之园主题的背景画面
The first change is that the title screen like with every new Minecraft update has been
updated to showcase the Pale Gardens Biome in the background.
1.21.4版本对掠夺者生物进行了若干调整
Changes have been made to the Pillager Mob in 1.21.4.
那么这个改动是什么呢
Now what is this change you may ask?
原来掠夺者生物会惧怕新加入的吱嘎怪  只要它们靠近  掠夺者就会逃跑
Well the Pillager Mob is actually afraid of the new Creaking Mob as it will run away from them if they're nearby.
别怕掠夺者
Don't worry Pillager,
我也觉得它们挺吓人的
I find them scary as well.
末影箱在花园觉醒更新中  也迎来了改动
Ender Chests have also been changed in the Garden Awakens update.
虽然改动不大  但现在末影箱若用错误工具开采  会掉落黑曜石而非空无一物
It's a small change but Ender Chests will now drop Obsidian if
they are mined with the wrong tool instead of dropping nothing at all.
说实话 这个末影箱拆得我怀疑人生  现在就是非常后悔
I'mma be real, this Ender Chest took absolutely ages to destroy and I really regret doing this.
但事实就是如此
But there you have it,
以上就是1.21.4花园觉醒版本新增的主要内容
those were most of the things that were added in the 1.21.4 Garden Awakens update.
为啥这更新名这么长啊老兄
Why is that update name so long man,
为啥不直接叫1.22呢
why can't they just call it 1.22?
总之 感谢观看
Anyways, thanks for watching,
留意那些吱呀作响的动静  我们下期再见
keep a look out for the Creaking and I'll see you all next time,
再见！
goodbye!
我的世界1.21.5版本正式上线！
Minecraft 1.21.5 is officially here!
生机焕发更新带来了新品种的鸡
The Spring to Life update has added new chickens,
新增了猪和牛  还有萤火虫灌木丛
pigs and cows, new firefly bushes,
新建筑生成点  以及更多精彩内容
new structure spawns and much much more.
本期视频我将全面盘点  生机焕发更新的所有新内容
So in this video I will be recapping every new feature added in the Spring to Life update.
我的世界新增了奶牛品种！
Minecraft has added new cows!
自2010年以来我们只有这种牛
Since 2010 the only cow we've had is this guy,
但在1.21.5版本中  游戏新增了两种奶牛变种
but in 1.21.5 two new variants of the cow have been added to the game.
第一种是寒带奶牛
The first new cow variant is the cold cow which looks like this.
寒带奶牛自然生成于各种寒冷生物群系
The cold cow will of course spawn in a variety of cold temperature biomes in your Minecraft world.
包括所有针叶林及积雪针叶林变种
These biomes include any tiger biome or snowy tiger variation.
你也能在风袭丘陵和风袭森林找到它们
You can also find the cold cow in the windswept hills and windswept forest biomes respectively.
新增的第二种奶牛是
The next new cow variant that was added was,
热带奶牛
you guessed it, the warm cow.
热带奶牛长这样  生成于温暖生物群系
Now the warm cow looks like this and can spawn in a variety of warm biomes such as the savannah,
比如热带草原  丛林和恶地
the jungle and the badlands.
这次更新不仅新增两种奶牛
Now not only did we get two new cows,
早在2010年Alpha版本加入的原版奶牛也迎来了全新变化
the original cow added back in alpha 2010 has also received some changes.
所以在1.21.5版本中  原先的普通奶牛正式更名为温带奶牛
So in 1.21.5 the original cow that was simply known as cow has been renamed to the temperate cow.
这种牛变种仍会像之前一样在所有可能的生物群系中生成 除了寒带和温带的生物群系 那里将由新的牛代替它们出现
Now this pre-existing cow variant will still spawn in every biome it
could before except for the cold and warm biomes where the new cows will take its place.
原版奶牛的纹理也进行了调整  主要变化是鼻子部分  现在会略微凸出面部模型 而此前是完全平坦的
The original cow has also received a texture change with the main change being
that its nose will now extrude from its model whereas before it was completely flat.
沙漠生物群系将在1.21.5版本迎来华丽升级
The desert biome is receiving a glow up in 1.21.5.
沙漠中现在会生成这种仙人掌花
That's right, in deserts you can now find the cactus flower which looks like this.
这是一种新型花朵  在沙漠和恶地群系的仙人掌上都有几率自然生成
This is a new type of flower which has a chance of generating on cactuses in both deserts and badland biomes.
有趣的是 当仙人掌高度为1-2格时  生成仙人掌花的概率会提升至10%  而非原先继续长高的情况
What's interesting is if a cactus is one or two blocks high the cactus flower
has a 10% chance to grow instead of the cactus getting higher.
沙漠群系在本更新中也将焕发生机  因为现在你能看到这种低矮的旱地新草丛
Desert biomes should also look a bit lively in this update as you can now
also find this new short dry grass that looks like this.
对了 还有这种更高大的旱地草丛
Oh there's also a tall version of the dry grass as well.
接下来要介绍的是  大家期待已久的萤火虫
Now the next feature we're going to talk about are the long awaited fireflies.
相信多数玩家都知道  萤火虫原本计划作为生物加入1.19荒野更新
So I'm sure most of you know fireflies were planned to be added as
a mob back in the 1.19 wild update.
这些萤火虫原本是2像素大小的生物  计划在沼泽群系的夜晚生成  并可能成为青蛙的食物
These fireflies were a 2 pixel mob and they were going to spawn
in swamp biomes at night and could be frogs.
然而开发者最终决定废弃这个版本的萤火虫生物  此后很长一段时间  我们都未再听闻相关消息 直到1.21.5版本
However the devs decided to scrap this version of the firefly mob and we
didn't really hear much about it up until 1.21.5.
没错  Minecraft最新更新重新加入了萤火虫
That's right Minecraft's newest update has re-added the firefly.
不过准确来说
Well sort of.
这次我们获得的不是萤火虫生物  而是这种萤火虫灌木丛
Instead of getting the firefly mob we have received the firefly bush that looks like this.
这种萤火虫灌木丛会自然生成在沼泽群系  当夜幕降临时就会出现超酷的效果
This firefly bush can be found in swamp biomes and
when it becomes night something really cool happens.
当夜幕降临  萤火虫灌木周围会浮现发光的萤火虫粒子效果  并提供2级亮度 扩散范围可达5格
So when it's dark glowing firefly particles will appear around the firefly bush
emitting a light level of 2 and expanding up to 5 blocks.
现在的萤火虫是单像素粒子效果  而非之前设计的双像素生物
The fireflies themselves are a single pixel particle instead of the 2 pixel mob we had before.
尽管我觉得萤火虫灌木很酷但我还是更喜欢 最初萤火虫生物的设计你们觉得呢 在评论区告诉我吧
Now despite how cool I find this firefly bush I still think I prefer the original
idea for the firefly but let me know in the comments.
树木迎来了重大改动
Trees have received a big change.
在1.21.5版本中你能在世界里遇到倒下的树木了
So in 1.21.5 you can now come across fallen trees in your Minecraft world.
这些是树木的变种  看起来像是被砍伐过  或是自然倒伏的树干
These are a subtype of tree that appear as if they have been cut or have fallen down.
倒下的树木共有4种变体  分别是橡木
The fallen trees can be found in 4 different variants which are oak,
桦木 丛林木和云杉木
birch, jungle and spruce.
这些倒下的树木很可能是为了与基岩版中 已存在多年的倒下树木保持一致而添加的
These fallen trees were likely added to match up with the fallen trees
that were already in bedrock edition and have been for many years.
所以现在Java版玩家  也能看到倒伏的树木了
So yeah, Java players can now also enjoy a tree that has fallen down.
Minecraft新增了鸡的变种
Minecraft has added new chickens.
首先是寒带鸡  它的外观长这样
First up we have the cold chicken which looks like this.
这种新型鸡变种  会在多种寒冷生物群系中生成
This new variant of chicken can spawn in a variety of cold temperature biomes.
包括针叶林生物群系
These include the tiger biomes,
雪原针叶林群系  以及最后的风袭丘陵群系
the snowy tiger biomes and finally the windswept biomes.
值得注意的是 普通鸡将不再生成于这些寒冷生物群系中  因为发型炫酷的寒带鸡将取代它们的位置
It's worth noting that regular chickens can no longer spawn in these cold temperature biomes
as this cold chicken will now take its place with its cool haircut.
寒带鸡不仅拥有炫酷发型
Not only do cold chickens have an awesome haircut,
它们还能产出独特的鸡蛋
they can also lay their own unique eggs.
这些蓝色鸡蛋当然能孵化出寒带鸡  但也能像普通鸡蛋一样用来制作蛋糕
These blue eggs are of course used to spawn cold chickens
but you can also craft cakes with them just like the regular eggs.
另一种新增的鸡是热带鸡
The other chicken type that was added is the warm chicken.
热带鸡的外形是这样的  它们会生成在各类温暖生物群系  比如热带草原
Now the warm chicken looks like this and can spawn in a variety of warm biomes such as the savannah,
丛林和恶地群系
the jungle and the badlands.
这些热带鸡还会产下这种棕色的蛋  扔出后自然也有概率孵化出热带鸡
These guys will also lay brown eggs that look like this
which when thrown will of course have a chance to hatch a warm chicken.
1.21.5版本对鞘翅做了个小改动
A small change was made to elytras in 1.21.5.
在本次更新前若玩家穿着鞘翅撞上梯子只会直接碰撞并死亡
So before this update if the player flew an elytra into a
ladder then they would just collide with it and die.
但在“生机焕发”更新中当玩家滑翔至 可攀爬的方块如梯子、脚手架和藤蔓时 鞘翅飞行会被立即中断
However in the spring to life update elytra flights are now cancelled
when you glide into climbable blocks such as ladders, scaffolding and vines.
以百万英里时速撞上梯子  却突然切换成攀爬姿势这感觉太诡异了
It's weird flying an elytra into a ladder at like a million miles an hour and it
just puts me in the climbing position.
1.21.5版本新增的另一个方块是落叶层方块
Another block that was added in the 1.21.5 update is the leaf litter block.
落叶层会自然生成在森林等生物群系的地表
The leaf litter can be found scattered around in biomes such as the forest,
深色森林和繁茂恶地群系
dark forests and wooded badlands.
落叶层方块的设计初衷  是模拟树木凋落的枯叶  我认为这为游戏增添了更多真实感
Now the leaf litter block is meant to resemble dead leaves that have fallen from the trees
which I think adds a bit more realism to the trees themselves.
哦对了 当你走过落叶层时它们还会发出独特的声响
Oh and the leaf litter will also make a unique sound when you walk on them.
落叶层可作为熔炉燃料  由于在上述生物群系中随处可见  你完全可以
The leaf litter can be used as fuel in a furnace
and since it will be found everywhere in the mentioned biomes you can
大量收集它们  就能在游戏初期轻松熔炼物品
collect a lot of them to have easy smelting during the first few days of your minecraft world.
另一种获取落叶层的方法  是将任意树叶方块放入熔炉烧制
Another way you can obtain leaf litters is by smelting any leaf block in a furnace.
知识就是力量
The more you know.
说到树叶方块
While we're on the topic of leaf blocks,
树叶本身也迎来了一些很酷的更新  这些变化体现在树木自然生成的树叶上
some cool changes have been made to the leaves themselves that generate on trees.
我们都知道樱花群系中的樱花树下方会飘落唯美的粒子效果
So we all know the cherry blossom trees in cherry grove biomes
have beautiful particle effects falling beneath the leaves.
而在1.21.5版本中  橡树
Well in 1.21.5 tree leaves with oak,
云杉 桦木 金合欢
spruce, birch, acacia,
丛林 深色橡木 红树林
jungle, dark oak, mangrove,
杜鹃和盛开的杜鹃树叶下  现在也会飘落粒子效果了
azalea and flowering azalea will now all have particles falling from them.
老实说  刚才报的树种名确实有点多
I can't lie, that was a lot of tree leaves to name.
不过现在  所有有树木的生物群系都会显得更有氛围感了  因为随时都能看到落叶纷飞的景象
But yeah, every biome containing trees should now look a lot more atmospheric
as you'll always see particles falling from the leaf blocks.
猪自2009年加入我的世界以来始终只有这一种经典造型
Pigs have been in minecraft since 2009 and we've only ever had one
variant since it was added which is this guy.
但在1.21.5版本中这个情况终于改变了  游戏新增了两种全新的猪猪变种
But that has changed in 1.21.5 as once again two new variants of the pig have been added.
就像牛群有不同变种一样  现在新增了寒带猪  和热带猪两种新外观
Just like the cows we have a cold pig that looks like this and a warm pig that looks like this.
这造型是不是绝了？
Don't they just look amazing?
现在寒带猪的生成群系与寒带牛相同正如之前提到的 它们会生成在针叶林生物群系及其变种 以及风袭生物群系和它的变种中
Now the cold pig has the same biome spawn as the cold cow which as I mentioned spawned in the tiger biome and
its variants as well as the windswept biome plus its variant.
热带猪会出现在  所有热带草原生物群系中
The warm pigs can be found in all savannah biomes,
丛林生物群系及其所有变种  最后还有恶地生物群系
the jungle biomes plus all of its variants and finally the badland biomes.
就像原版牛一样
Just like the original cow,
原版猪现已更名为温带猪  由于新增变种机制它们将不再生成于热带与寒带生物群系中
the OG pig has been renamed from pig to temperate pig
and can no longer spawn in the warm and cold biomes due to the new
猪的新变种将取代它们的位置
variants of the pigs taking their place.
不过别担心  这些经典款在其他所有生物群系  依然能见到它们的身影
You can still find these legends in every other biome though so don't worry.
在“春日复苏”更新中  苍白之园生物群系已进行了调整
A change has been made to the pale garden biome in the spring to life update.
因此在1.21.5版本之前苍白之园生物群系  不仅生成概率极低规模也很小
So before 1.21.5 the pale garden was rather difficult to find
and when you did find one the biome was always quite small.
整体而言在1.21.5版本中  苍白之园的生成频率大幅提升且生物群系规模显著扩大
However in 1.21.5 the pale garden will now generate a lot
more frequently and the biome itself will be a lot larger overall.
1.21.5版本对林地府邸结构进行了一项美观性调整
The woodland mansion structure received a pretty change in 1.21.5.
众所周知  林地府邸原本只生成于黑森林生物群系
So we all know woodland mansions generate in dark forest biomes
but in the spring to life update the structure will also
现在林地府邸也能在苍白之园中生成
be able to generate in pale gardens as well.
而由于这种建筑结构原本就极其稀有
And since this structure was so incredibly rare before,
这项改动或许能让府邸遗迹变得稍微常见些  毕竟现在它们能在两种不同生物群系中生成
this change will perhaps make the mansion a bit more common to find as
they can now spawn in two different biomes.
真奇怪  林地府邸出现在苍白之园里总感觉哪里不对劲
I don't know why but it's so weird seeing a woodland mansion in a pale garden.
在1.21.5版本中请留意一种名为野花簇的新花卉
In 1.21.5 be on the lookout for a new flower which is known as the wildflower.
这种新型花卉可以在桦木森林中生长
This new type of flower can grow in birch forests,
古老桦木森林  以及草甸生物群系中生长
old growth birch forests and the meadows biome.
这种花卉非常独特  单格方块内最多可生长4朵野花簇  与粉瓣花的特性相似
This flower is unique as it can have up to 4 wildflowers within a single block similar to the pink petals.
你还可以将野花簇合成黄色染料 但我更愿意纯粹欣赏这朵花有多酷
You can also craft the wildflowers into yellow dye but I prefer to just look at how cool the flower looks.
蜜蜂在“生命复苏”更新中迎来了新变化
Bees have received a change in the spring to life update.
既然这次更新加入了野花簇和仙人掌花
That's right, since wildflowers and cactus flowers were added in this update,
蜜蜂现在也能为这些新花卉授粉了
bees will now be able to pollinate them.
不仅如此  你还可以用野花簇和仙人掌花来繁殖蜜蜂
Not only that but you can also use wildflowers and cactus flowers to breed bees as well.
现在来说说沙漠生物群系  这次更新为它添加了新的环境音效
Now let's talk about the desert biome as it has received some new ambient sounds in this update.
当你在沙漠探索时可能会听到来自沙子的环境音效
That's right, when exploring a desert biome you have a chance to hear ambient sounds playing from the sand,
陶瓦方块  甚至枯灌木也会发出声响
terracotta blocks and even the dead bushes.
信标方块在本次更新中获得了一个小改动
The beacon block has received a small update in Minecraft.
在1.21.5版本中  信标光束会随着距离玩家越远渲染得越宽
That's right, in 1.21.5 the beacon's beam has been changed to be rendered wider the further it is from the player.
我猜这个改动是为了让信标从远处更容易被发现
I assume this change was done to make the beacon more visible from afar.
现在信标光束最高可渲染2048格高度  而之前只有1024格
Oh and the beacon's beam will now also render up to 2048 blocks high instead of only 1024 blocks.
1.21.5版本对嘎枝生物做了一个小调整
A small change has been made to the creaking mob in 1.21.5.
以前无法用命名牌给嘎枝命名  但现在可以了
So before you were not able to name creakings with a name tag but in 1.21.5 you can.
这也意味着被命名的嘎枝将不会消失 会一直存在于你的世界中
This also means that creakings named with a name tag will persist throughout the day and won't despawn in your world so
小心点
be careful.
1.21.5版本还新增了这些测试方块大概是为了测试游戏机制？
1.21.5 also added these new test blocks to I guess test the game's mechanics?
说实话  我完全搞不懂这些方块的机制  但应该是给玩家和Mojang自己  用来测试
I'll be real I have no idea how they work but I assume they're used by the player and Mojang themselves to test the
游戏代码中的漏洞
game's code to find bugs.
不过看起来还挺有意思的
But yeah, they look interesting.
1.21.5版本中磁石方块迎来了重大改动
In 1.21.5 the lodestone block received a major change.
磁石的作用是改变指南针指向  让它不再指向出生点  而是指向磁石方块本身
So the lodestone is used to alter your compass by having it point towards the block instead of your usual spawn point.
在此次更新前  磁石方块的合成配方是8个錾制石砖加1个下界合金锭
Now before this update the block was crafted with 8 chiselled stone bricks and a netherite ingot.
但在1.21.5版本中磁石方块的合成配方 改为8个錾制石砖加1个铁锭
However, in 1.21.5 the lodestone is now crafted with 8 chiselled stone bricks and an iron ingot.
这个改动意义重大  现在磁石方块更容易合成  而且可以无限再生了
This is a big change as the block can be crafted a lot easier now and is also renewable.
对了 现在你还能在主世界的废弃传送门宝箱里找到磁石方块
Oh and you can also now find lodestone blocks in a ruined portal chest in the overworld.
现在你可以更轻松地用指南针控制重生点了
So yeah, you can now definitely control your spawn point with compasses a lot easier.
就像如今的每次我的世界更新一样
Like with every new Minecraft update nowadays,
标题界面的背景图已更新为与最新版本主题相契合的风格
the title screen background has been updated to match the theme of Minecraft's newest update.
我特别喜欢这个新背景  因为它完整展现了仙人掌开花的全新形态
I'm a fan of this background because you really get to see the new cactus flower in full form.
我的世界1.21.5版本新增了一个方块
Minecraft 1.21.5 has received a new block,
灌木丛
the bush.
这些灌木丛  可以在平原生物群系中找到
These bushes can be found in the plains biome,
疾风高原生物群系  森林生物群系  以及白桦林生物群系
the windswept biome, the forest biome and finally the birch forest biome.
和草丛一样  这些灌木会随所处生物群系改变颜色 这意味着它们能
Just like the grass, these bushes will change colour depending on the biome they are placed in which means they'll make
成为相当不错的装饰性方块
for quite a nice decorative block.
虽然只是灌木丛  但它确实为一些略显过时的生物群系增添了更多生机
Now I know it's just a bush but it does add more life to some of the biomes that were beginning to outdated.
我的世界中的羊群机制有所调整
Sheep in Minecraft have been changed.
在1.21.5版本中  绵羊的毛色将取决于它们生成的生物群系
So in 1.21.5 the colour of the sheep's wool will now be based on which biome they spawn in.
例如在寒冷生物群系
For example, in cold temperature biomes,
黑羊将成为最常见的品种
black sheep will now be the most common sheep to find here.
寒冷地带也能发现灰羊
In cold biomes you will also be able to find grey sheep,
浅灰羊  白羊和棕羊  但出现概率较低
light grey sheep, white sheep and brown sheep but this is less common.
当然你依然能找到极其稀有的粉红羊  这点无需担心
And finally in the biomes you can still find the super rare pink sheep so don't worry about that.
至于温带生物群系的羊群分布
Moving on to the sheep spawns for warm biomes,
例如在恶地和沙漠群系  最常见的将是棕羊
the most common sheep you will find in badlands and deserts for example are the brown sheep.
你也能发现灰羊
You will also be able to find grey sheep,
浅灰羊  白羊与黑羊  但同样较为罕见
light grey sheep, white sheep and black sheep but again they are less common.
噢别担心  温暖群系同样会刷新粉红羊  只不过依旧极其稀有
Oh and don't worry, warm biomes can also contain a pink sheep as well but it's very rare once again.
1.21.5版本中  温带群系（即其他所有群系）  的羊群分布保持不变
In 1.21.5 sheep spawns for temperate biomes aka every other biome in the game will remain the same.
这意味着白羊仍是这些区域最常见的品种  而灰羊
This means white sheep will still be the most common sheep to find here while grey,
浅灰羊  黑羊与棕羊  则较为少见
light grey, black and brown sheep will be less common to encounter.
不过温带群系的粉红羊已被移除
Pink sheep however in temperate biomes have been removed.
开玩笑的啦  它们仍可能出现在所有群系  只不过依旧非常稀有
Nah I'm joking they can still spawn in every biome but still remain very rare.
关于这次羊群调整  有趣的是在1.21.5的早期快照中  其他毛色变种
Now what's interesting about these sheep changes is that in a previous snapshot for 1.21.5 other sheep colours were able
也曾能自然生成
to naturally spawn.
没错 在寒冷群系中有机会遇见浅蓝色羊
That's right, in cold biomes you were able to find light blue sheep,
浅蓝羊  与青蓝羊  但这项改动已被回滚
blue sheep and cyan sheep naturally but this change was reverted.
在之前的快照版本中  温带群系里你还能遇见黄色绵羊
In a previous snapshot for the warm biomes you were able to find yellow sheep,
橙羊  与红羊  自然生成  虽然我觉得这设定超酷
orange sheep and red sheep naturally as well which I think would have been really cool to encounter but yeah this change
这项改动也在后续快照中被撤销了
was also reverted in a later snapshot.
1.21.5版本的下一个改动是针对绵羊外观本身的调整
The next change in 1.21.5 is a change that was made to the sheep's appearance itself.
所以在本次更新中  绵羊的内层绒毛现在会与外部羊毛颜色保持一致
So in this update the undercoats of sheep will now be coloured to match their wool colour.
例如这只粉色绵羊  被剪毛后现在会保留粉色斑块来体现原本毛色  而不再是
For example, this pink sheep when sheared will now have pink patches to represent its wool colour instead of having
原先的白色斑块
white patches like it did before.
这项改动是为了与基岩版保持一致  因为该特性早已存在于基岩版中
This change was done to match Minecraft Bedrock Edition as this sheep feature was already in that version of the game.
不仅绵羊的内层绒毛发生了变化
Not only was the sheep's undercoat changed,
它们的面部毛发也做出了调整
the sheep's face was also changed as well.
没错 在1.21.5版本中  绵羊面部将不再统一显示白色羊毛  而是会
That's right, in 1.21.5 the sheep's face will no longer have white wool for every sheep colour and will instead have
根据染色类型  呈现对应颜色的面部毛发
wool on its face to match the dye colour it has.
同样 这项改动也是为了同步基岩版既有特性  不过说实话
Again, this change was done to match a feature that was already in Bedrock Edition but yeah,
看着这只满脸蓝毛的绵羊  确实有点违和感
it's weird seeing this blue sheep with blue wool on its face.
Minecraft在1.21.5版本中彻底重制了刷怪蛋的外观
Minecraft has completely overhauled the appearance of spawn eggs in 1.21.5.
没错 本次更新后  创造模式菜单里的所有刷怪蛋材质都经过重新设计
That's right, in this update every spawn egg in the creative mode menu has had its texture changed to make them easier
以便更好地区分不同生物
to distinguish from one another.
例如 这是苦力怕的刷怪蛋
For example, this is the creeper spawn egg,
这是猪的刷怪蛋
this is the pig spawn egg,
这是嗅探兽的刷怪蛋
here's the sniffer spawn egg,
这是末影人的刷怪蛋  这是熊猫的刷怪蛋
the enderman egg, the panda,
这是美西螈的刷怪蛋
the axolotl.
我想你应该明白了
I think you get the point.
起初我对这个改动持保留态度  但现在觉得每个刷怪蛋都有专属图标  确实比千篇一律
At first I wasn't sure about this change but it is cool that each spawn egg has its own unique icon instead of them all
全都采用同款斑点蛋  仅颜色不同的旧设计强多了
just being a coloured variant of the same spotted egg we had before.
话虽如此  我还是会怀念多年来熟悉的旧版刷怪蛋
That being said, I am going to miss the original spawn egg we've been used to for so many years so on that note I have
在此我要说  永别了 经典的刷怪蛋
to say, rest in peace OG spawn egg,
我们会想念你的
you will be missed.
既然1.21.5版本新增了刷怪蛋
Since we have new spawn eggs in 1.21.5,
创造模式物品栏进行了一项小改动
a small change was made to the creative mode inventory.
刷怪蛋物品栏标签页的图标已从旧版猪刷怪蛋  更换为新版苦力怕刷怪蛋
That's right, the spawn egg inventory tab has been changed from the old pig spawn egg icon to the new creeper spawn egg
这个新图标我觉得确实挺酷的
icon which I think looks cool actually.
狼在1.21.5版本中获得了一个相当酷的改动
Wolves have received a pretty cool change in 1.21.5.
众所周知我的世界最近为不同生物群系添加了狼的变种  而这次更新又带来了全新的
So we all know Minecraft recently added wolf variants for different biomes but in this update we have now received new
狼的叫声
wolf sounds as well.
没错  现在狼生成时  会随机播放一种叫声变体  这些新叫声如下所示
That's right, wolves will now receive a random sound variant when they spawn and those new sounds are as followed.
首先是愤怒的嚎叫
First up we have angry.
接下来是名为“雄浑”的狼嚎
Next up are wolf sounds called big.
接下来是名为“萌系”的狼嚎
Next up are wolf sounds called cute.
接下来是名为“暴躁”的狼嚎
Next up we have wolf sounds that are called grump.
接下来是名为“猪灵”的狼嚎
Next up we have a wolf sound file called puglin.
最后是名为“哀伤”的狼嚎
And finally we have wolf sounds that are called sad.
现在你想知道
Now in case you were wondering,
我们熟悉且喜爱的经典狼嚎  依然会保留在原版游戏中
the original wolf sounds we know and love aren't going anywhere.
没这些经典怀旧的狼嚎声  仍会保留2011年以来的原版经典狼身上
That's right, these original old school wolf sounds will still be used for the original classic wolf we've had since 2011.
真高兴他们没有移除这些老伙计
I'm so glad they're not removing these man,
这些声音太让人怀念了
they're so nostalgic.
在1.21.5“生机盎然”更新中
In the 1.21.5 spring to life update,
铁栏杆 方块 活板门
iron bars, blocks, trapdoors,
门和压力板  现在都拥有了专属音效
doors and pressure plates have all received their own unique sounds.
听听看
Take a listen.
在这次更新中  哞菇牛获得了一些小改动
The mooshroom cow has received some small changes in this update.
所以在1.21.5版本中  红色和棕色的哞菇牛都更新了纹理贴图  现在它们的鼻子都突出在外了
So in 1.21.5 both the red and brown mooshroom cow have had their textures updated to now have their snout extruded out
不再像以前那样是扁平的了
instead of being flat like it was before.
这项改动是为了与近期更新的普通牛和新品种牛的纹理调整保持一致
This change was done to match the texture changes recently made to the regular and new cows respectively.
落叶堆现在放置时会根据生物群系改变颜色
Leaf litters will now use the biome colouring system when it's placed.
比如放在森林群系会呈现这种颜色  而在寒冷的雪原群系则会变成这样
For example if you place it in a forest biome it will look like this but in a cold snowy biome it will look like this
呈现出截然不同的棕色色调
being a much different shade of brown.
所以不妨在每个生物群系都放置落叶堆   看看它们的颜色差异吧
So yeah, place a leaf litter in every biome and see the colour difference,
我想不出比这更有趣的我的世界玩法了
I couldn't possibly think of anything more fun to do in Minecraft.
骆驼在1.21.5版本中会更容易找到
Camels will be more common to find in 1.21.5.
这是因为骆驼现在会自然生成于沙漠群系这一机制发生了变动
This is because a change was made to where camels will now spawn naturally in desert biomes.
此前骆驼只会在沙漠村庄中生成  现在它们会出现在整个沙漠群系  这样的改动真是太棒了
Before camels could only spawn in desert villages specifically so it's cool you'll now see them in the desert biome itself.
收纳袋是个相当实用的物品  能存放多达一组的混合类物品
The bundle is a rather useful item that can store up to a stack's worth of mixed item types.
在此次更新前  收纳袋只能由玩家合成  无法在世界中自然获取
Now before this update bundles could only be crafted by the player and couldn't be found anywhere in your world.
但在1.21.5版本中  现在村庄的箱子里也能找到收纳袋了
But in 1.21.5 bundles can now be found in chests within villages which is pretty cool as my inventory legit gets full
搜刮村庄不到5分钟  背包就塞得满满当当
within 5 minutes of looting a village.
羊的机制也迎来了一项重大改动  让我来告诉你们这个重磅变化
Another change has been made to sheep and let me tell you guys it is a big change.
各位准备好  因为在1.21.5版本中  羊现在可以吃蕨类植物了
Get ready guys because in 1.21.5 sheep can now eat fern.
你们都知道蕨类植物是什么吧
You guys know what fern is right?
就是那种生长在针叶林里的灌木变种  平时根本没人注意  但它们确实存在
You know, that bush variant that's found in tiger biomes that no one ever really looks at but it's there?
现在羊可以吃它们了
Yeah well sheep can eat them now.
这改动意义重大  因为玩家薅走羊毛做床后  羊现在有了新的恢复途径
This is huge as sheep will now have a new way to regrow their wool after the player stole it to make a bed.
还需注意的是  这项改动是为了与基岩版同步  因为基岩版的羊早就能食用蕨类植物了
Another thing to note is this change was made to match bedrock edition as sheep in bedrock could already eat fern before this update
这次更新确实是基岩版抢先一步了
So yeah bedrock beat us to it.
本次更新对马匹做了一处小调整
A small change has been made to horses in this update.
所以在1.21.5版本之前  如果给马匹装备了鞍具  然后让马进入隐身状态  马和鞍具会同时消失
So before 1.21.5 if a horse had a saddle equipped but was then made invisible
the horse along with the saddle itself would disappear.
但在1.21.5版本中  当装备鞍具的马匹被施加隐身药水时  鞍具会继续保持可见
However in 1.21.5 when the horse with a saddle is given an invisibility potion the saddle itself will still remain
这才是正确的设定
visible which is how it's meant to be.
我的世界1.21.6版本现已发布
Minecraft 1.21.6 is here.
追逐天际更新带来了全新生物
The chase the skies update has added new mobs,
全新方块  全新机制  以及更多精彩内容
new blocks, new mechanics and much much more.
在本视频中  我将为大家展示  追逐天际更新的所有新特性
So in this video I'll be showing you every new feature added in the chase the skies update.
我的世界1.21.6带来了史上最重大的变革之一
Minecraft 1.21.6 has brought one of the biggest changes in history.
鞍具自2010年就存在于我的世界中  但自加入游戏以来  玩家始终无法通过合成获得它们
So saddles have been in Minecraft since 2010 and ever since they were added you were never able to craft them.
你只能在地牢中找到鞍具
Instead you could only find a saddle in dungeons,
沙漠神殿  以及要塞宝箱中获得鞍具
desert temples and stronghold chests.
但在追逐天际更新中  这一切都发生了改变  鞍具现在可以合成制作了
But that has all changed in the chase the skies update as saddles are now craftable.
只需在工作台上  摆放3块皮革和1个铁锭  就能合成出鞍具
Just simply put 3 leather with 1 iron ingot in a crafting table and bam you have a saddle.
真不敢相信这终于实现了
I can't believe this is finally possible,
这个改动足足等了15年才实现
it's only taken 15 years to get this change.
此外 由于新版本中鞍具可以合成制作  它们将不再出现在  我之前提到的那些建筑结构中
Additionally since you can now craft saddles in the new update you can no longer find them in the structures I mentioned before.
追逐天际更新中  云朵迎来了一项超酷的改动
Clouds have received a pretty cool change in the chase the skies update.
没错 在1.21.6版本中  云朵分布的材质贴图已更新  现在天空中会出现更多云彩
That's right in 1.21.6 the texture for cloud distribution has been updated to have more clouds in the sky along with
云朵之间的间隙  也变得更小了
smaller gaps in between.
此外 当特定云朵相互排列时  还有极小概率会形成苦力怕脸的云朵图案
Additionally there is also a rare chance for the clouds to form a creeper face when certain clouds align with each other.
虽然这种现象相当罕见  但确实非常酷炫
Now this is quite a rare event but really cool nonetheless.
Minecraft 1.21.6版本在下界新增了一种方块
Minecraft 1.21.6 has added a new block to the nether.
因此 如果你在下界探索灵魂沙峡谷生物群系  就有可能遇到这种造型奇特的方块
So if you explore the soul sand valley biome within the nether then you may stumble across this odd looking block.
这就是失水恶魂
This is the Dried ghast.
在灵魂沙谷的幽冥化石间发现的失水恶魂 形似静止无害的恶魂以方块形态呈现
Found between nether fossils in soul sand valleys the Dried ghast
resembles an immobile harmless ghast that takes the form of a block.
失水恶魂可以用任何工具或徒手立即采集 但你也可以通过使用8个恶魂之泪和一个骨头块来合成一个
The Dried ghast can instantly be collected by the any tool or by hand
but you can also craft one by using 8 ghast tears and a bone block.
另一种获取失水恶魂方块的方式  是与猪灵以物易物
Another way you can obtain the Dried ghast block is by bartering with piglins.
如果你向猪灵投掷金锭进行交易  就有2.13%的概率会给你
That's right if you throw gold ingots at a piglin to barter then there is a 2.13% chance for a piglin to give you a Dried ghast block.
失水恶魂的主要特性在于它能被带回主世界
Now the main feature of the Dried ghast is that it can be taken back to the overworld,
放置后  玩家可以将其浸入水中
placed down and then be waterlogged by the player.
失水恶魂浸入水中后  会分阶段开始  再水合过程
The Dried ghast when submerged in water will then begin a rehydration process that happens in stages.
第一阶段是原始干燥状态  看起来一脸暴躁
The first stage is the original dried stage which looks all grumpy.
然而在水中浸泡5分钟后  干燥的失水恶魂会进入部分水合状态  外观会变得稍微明亮些
After 5 minutes however of being in water the dried ghast becomes partially hydrated looking a bit brighter.
10分钟后  方块进入基本水合状态  看起来没那么暴躁了 15分钟后露出开心的表情
After 10 minutes the block becomes mostly hydrated looking slightly less
grumpy and then after 15 minutes the dried ghast becomes happy looking,
变为完全水合状态
being fully hydrated.
我超爱这块失水恶魂方块最初暴躁的模样  随着水合程度加深  逐渐变得明亮欢快的样子
I just love how this ghast block starts off grumpy looking but becomes brighter and happier the more it hydrates.
相信很多人都和这个失水恶魂方块感同身受
I'm sure a lot of us have felt like this ghast block.
总之 当干燥的失水恶魂  在水中浸泡20分钟后它会变成“逐梦苍穹”更新中新增的首个生物
Anyways, after 20 minutes of the dried ghast being submerged in water it transforms into the
first new mob has been added in the chase the skies update.
这就是小恶魂
Meet the ghastling.
一种小型被动型恶魂生物不会向你发射火球 但偶尔会在16格范围内跟随玩家或其他生物
A small passive ghast mob that won't shoot fireballs at you but will instead occasionally
follow the player or other mobs within a 16 block radius.
但大多数时候  小恶魂只会漫无目的地飘荡  安安静静地待在自己的小世界里
But most of the time the ghastling will just float around aimlessly and just mind their own business really.
然而小恶魂只会维持这个状态约20分钟  之后就会蜕变成体型更大的
However, the ghastling will only remain in this state for about 20 minutes as it will transform into a much bigger,
更友善的恶魂生物  它被正式命名为快乐恶魂
friendlier ghast mob that has officially been named as the happy ghast.
不过关于小恶魂有个很酷的设定  你可以投喂雪球来加速它们的成长进程
One cool thing to note about the ghastling though is that you can feed them snowballs to
speed up the process in which they become a happy ghast.
只需投喂10个或更多雪球  就能看着它们迅速蜕变成这只友善的巨型恶魂
Just give them 10 or more snowballs and watch them quickly transform into this big friendly ghast.
那么现在  我们来聊聊快乐恶魂
Now then, let's talk about the happy ghast.
快乐恶魂是一种会在主世界  漫无目的漂浮的生物  但脸上始终挂着笑容
So the happy ghast is a mob that will float around aimlessly in the overworld but with a smile on its face.
这个生物完全被动无害
The mob is completely passive,
拥有10颗心的生命值  被击杀时会掉落1-3颗经验球
has 10 hearts of health and will drop 1-3 experience orbs when killed.
但你们可别想着从快乐恶魂身上捞经验球啊
But you guys won't be getting experience orbs off a happy ghast because you wouldn't be so horrible as to kill one would you?
嘿 我那次不算数的
Hey, it doesn't count that I did it,
为了视频效果我不得不这么做
I had to do it for the sake of the video,
这不算数的 懂吗
it doesn't count okay?
不过话说回来  快乐恶魂还能提供  一种全新的主世界旅行方式  原因如下
But anyways, the happy ghast will also serve as a brand new way to travel around the overworld and here is why.
所以如果你能收集到3块皮革
So if you manage to collect 3 leather,
1只恶魂  加上一些羊毛
1 ghast and some wool,
就能像这样在工作台上合成  制作出全新物品——挽具
you can put them together in the crafting table like so and craft a brand new item which is known as the harness.
挽具外观如图所示  共有16种颜色变体  具体取决于你使用的羊毛颜色
Now the harness looks like this and comes in 16 different colour variants which is based on which wool colour you used to craft it.
这个挽具可以装备在快乐恶魂身上
This harness can then be equipped to a happy ghast,
让恶魂头顶出现飞行员护目镜
changing the ghast's appearance to have aviator goggles above its head.
一旦装备好鞍具
Once the harness is equipped,
玩家就能骑乘快乐恶魂进行水平和垂直飞行
the player can ride the happy ghast and fly both horizontally and vertically,
实现更精准的空中移动
allowing for more precise movement in the air.
哦对了 当玩家骑乘时
Oh, also, while the happy ghast is being ridden by the player,
恶魂的护目镜会降下遮住眼睛变成这样 我觉得超酷的
its goggles lower to cover its eyes looking like this and I think that just looks amazing.
快乐恶魂最棒的地方在于最多可承载4名玩家
Now what's cool about the happy ghast is that it can be ridden by up to 4 players,
所以如果在多人服务器你和朋友们可以共用一个鞍具
so if you're playing on multiplayer servers then you and your friends can traverse the overworld using one harness on a
坐在一只咧嘴大笑的快乐恶魂上
big smiling ghast mob.
不过得由我来控制恶魂
I will be the one controlling the ghast though,
我可不信朋友们不会骑着我们撞上山崖
cause I don't trust my friends to not ride us into a cliff or something.
快乐恶魂不仅是探索世界的好帮手
Not only is the happy ghast great for exploring your world,
还是高空建筑的实用工具原因如下
it's also a very useful mob for building in high places and here is why.
玩家不仅能骑乘快乐恶魂
So not only can players ride happy ghasts,
还能像站在实心方块上那样站在它头顶
they can also stand on top of them as well as if they were a solid block.
此时恶魂会保持静止
The ghast will then still while players are standing on it.
这样上下坐骑更方便也能让玩家安心在高空施工
This makes it easier to both mount and dismount the mob as well as allowing players to build high above the ground
不必担心恶魂突然飞走
without the risk of their ghast flying away.
快乐恶魂还有个超棒的特性 能用拴绳在空中运输实体
Another really cool feature with happy ghasts is their ability to transport entities in the air by using leads.
举个例子 若玩家用拴绳将生物系在快乐恶魂上  就能实现空中运输
For example, if a player attaches a leashed mob to a happy ghast then you will be able to transport said mob from point
从A点运送到B点
A to point B.
快乐恶魂还能拴住船只  这意味着两名玩家可以同乘一艘船
A happy ghast is also able to have a leashed boat attached to them meaning you can have 2 players sitting in the boat
而快乐恶魂上还能承载4人
and 4 on the happy ghast,
让6人同时从A点飞往B点
allowing 6 of you to fly from point A to point B at once.
既然说到拴绳牵引生物这个话题
Now while we're on the topic of leashed mobs,
拴绳在1.21.6版本中迎来了几项重大改动
leads have received a few major changes in the 1.21.6 update.
首先 在此更新前  拴绳由4根线和1个粘液球合成
So first of all, leads before this update were crafted with 4 strings and 1 slime ball but in the chase update it was
现在只需5根线即可合成
changed to only use 5 strings.
这项改动可能是为了降低合成难度  毕竟粘液球的获取有时并不容易
This was likely done to make leads easier to craft as slime balls can sometimes be a bit difficult to obtain.
在“翱翔天际”更新中  拴绳机制本身也迎来了改动
Another change made to leads in the chase the skies update is a change made to the lead mechanics themselves.
众所周知 多个生物可以同时被拴绳牵引  但在1.21.6版本中 实体可被牵引的位置也新增了改动
So we all know multiple mobs can be held by leads at once but in 1.21.6 an additional change to where entities can be
拴绳现在可以将实体与其他实体相连
attached to other entities with leads.
例如 你可以用拴绳将多只猪串联起来  组成一支商队般的队列
For example, if you want to connect multiple pigs together in a caravan like fashion then you can.
猪群会以更有序的方式跟随你 不再像旧版本那样全都挤作一团
The pigs will also follow you in a much more organised state
instead of them all being bunched up together with the old lead method.
值得一提的是 新机制下你还可以用拴绳将船只相互连接
It's also worth noting that with the new lead mechanic you can also connect boats to other boats.
这意味着你可以在水中  用拴绳串联起一列船只
This means you can have a string of lead connected boats in the water which can allow you to do things such as transport
实现跨水域运输多只生物或带箱子的船只
many mobs or boats with chests across water.
但1.21.6版本中最酷的玩法  莫过于用拴绳配合快乐恶魂
But easily the coolest thing you can do with leads in 1.21.6 is utilise them with the happy ghast mob.
因为现在可以用拴绳  将快乐恶魂与其他实体相连
This is because leads can be connected to the happy ghast itself along with another entity.
这意味着你可以让快乐恶魂  用拴绳带着嗅探兽从A点飞到B点
This means you can use a happy ghast to carry a sniffer mob with the lead and transport it from point A to B.
你甚至可以让快乐恶魂牵引船只  而船只又连着另一艘载有嗅探兽的船
You can also use a happy ghast to carry a boat that's connected to another boat that's then been connected to a sniffer.
相信你已经明白其中妙处
I think you get the point.
利用快乐恶魂运输实体的可能性  简直无穷无尽
The possibilities of transporting entities with happy ghasts are just endless.
1.21.6版本对拴绳的其他小改动如下
Some small other changes made to leads in 1.21.6 are as follows.
首先 拴绳的断裂距离  从10格延长到了12格
First of all the distance in which a lead can snap and break has been increased from 10 blocks long to 12 blocks long.
但若拴绳连接的是快乐恶魂  断裂距离将增至16格
However the snapping distance with a lead will be 16 blocks long if it is attached to a happy ghast.
其次新增了一个细节  拴绳长度会随牵引生物体型自动调整
Secondly a nice detail added to the leads is depending on the size of the mob you're leashing the lead will extend into
延伸为四段长度
four sections when it's connected to said mob.
例如当我用拴绳连接嗅探兽和快乐恶魂时  由于嗅探兽体型庞大  你会看到拴绳自动分成了四段延伸
For example if I connect a sniffer to a happy ghast you'll see that the lead extends four ways as the sniffer is quite a large mob.
第三项关于拴绳的改动是  现在你可以用剪刀剪断连接两个实体之间的拴绳
Third of all another change made to leads is that you can now use shears to cut the leads if it is connected from one entity to another.
说到剪刀  它们也有一项改动
And while we're on the topic of shears a change was made to them as well.
因此在1.21.6版本中  剪刀现在可以用来移除鞍具
So in 1.21.6 shears are now able to be used to remove saddles,
马铠和挽具
horse armour and harnesses from mobs.
例如以前如果你给猪装上鞍  就只能通过杀死猪来移除鞍具
So for example before if you were to put a saddle on a pig then you weren't able to remove it unless you killed the pig.
但在“追逐天际”更新中  只需用剪刀右键点击已装鞍的猪  就能轻松取下鞍具
But in the chase the skies update just right click on the saddled pig with shears and there you go the saddle is removed.
在Minecraft 1.21.6版本中  对下界常见的恶魂进行了调整
In Minecraft 1.21.6 a change has been made to the regular ghasts we find in the nether.
首先 恶魂的材质分辨率已更新  并提升至双倍精度  以匹配新版本的快乐恶魂
First of all the resolution of the ghast texture has been updated and doubled to match the high resolution of the new happy ghasts.
“追逐天际”更新中  恶魂还有个很酷的改动  它们现在会掉落新的音乐唱片
Another cool change with ghasts in the chase the skies update is that they are now able to drop a new music disc.
没错 如果你通过反弹火球击杀恶魂  它就会掉落一张音乐唱片
That's right if you manage to kill a ghast by deflecting it's fireball then the ghast will actually drop a music disc
死亡时会掉落一张名为“tears”的唱片
upon death that is simply named tears.
这是新音乐唱片的效果试听
Here is a preview of how the new music disc sounds.
在1.21.6版本中主世界将焕然一新  游戏新增了环境雾气效果
The overworld is getting a glow up in 1.21.6 as a new type of environmental fog has been added into the game.
没错 在主世界下雨和雷暴天气时雾气效果会变得更为浓密
That's right during rain and thunderstorms in the overworld the fog will now appear as being a lot more denser and intense.
这项改动旨在让玩家在雨天获得更强烈的暴风雨氛围体验
This change was done to give the player a lot more of a stormy atmosphere when it rains in your world.
我的世界多人游戏模式在"追逐天际"更新中迎来了一些改动
Minecraft multiplayer has received some changes in the chase the skies update.
1.21.6版本新增了定位指针  会显示在玩家HUD界面上  主要用于指示方向
So 1.21.6 has added a new locator bar which will be displayed on the players HUD and essentially reveal the direction
以及同服务器其他玩家的具体位置
and location of other players that are playing on your multiplayer server.
如果玩家想隐藏自己不被定位指针显示  可以通过以下几种方式实现
Now if a player wants to hide from being shown on the locator bar then they can do a few things to counter it.
首先 若玩家进入潜行蹲伏状态  定位指针上将不会显示其位置
First of all if the player was to sneak and crouch then they won't show up on the locator bar.
玩家也可以戴上生物头颅或雕刻南瓜头来隐藏行踪
Players can also wear a mob head or a carved pumpkin.
最后 若玩家处于隐身药水效果下  同样不会在定位指针上显示位置
And finally if the player is under the invisibility effect then they won't appear on the locator bar as well.
需要注意的是 处于旁观者模式的玩家不会显示在定位指针上  但处于创造模式的玩家仍会被显示
It's also worth noting that players in spectator mode will not be visible either on the locator bar but people in creative mode will.
最后 随着今日更新的发布  我的世界标题界面背景  也同步更新为匹配当前版本的全新画面
And finally with every new update that's released today the Minecraft title screen background has been changed to match
与“追逐天际”主题相呼应
the theme of chase the skies.
例如 你可以在背景中看到一只欢快的恶魂  以及新加入的干枯恶魂方块
For example you can see a happy ghast in the background as well as the dried ghast block.
以上就是本次更新的全部内容
But there you have it,
以上就是1.21.6“追逐天际”版本更新的主要内容
those were most of the things added in the 1.21.6 chase the skies update.
不过无论如何 非常感谢大家的观看
But anyways thank you all so much for watching,
尽情骑着新版欢乐恶魂在主世界遨游吧  我们下期视频再见
enjoy traversing the overworld on the new happy ghasts mob and I'll see you all in my next video,
再见！
goodbye!
我的世界已发布下个更新的预览版
Minecraft has released a preview for the next update.
本次更新为铜质物品新增多项功能
This update adds many features to copper,
例如铜质工具
such as copper tools,
铜质盔甲 铜质箱子  以及万众期待的铜傀儡
copper armor, copper chests and most importantly the long awaited copper golem.
本期视频将为大家展示  我的世界全新版本的所有新增内容
So in this video I'll be showing you all the new features coming to Minecraft's newest update.
游戏将加入全新系列工具  由于本次更新本质上是“铜器更新”
Minecraft is adding brand new tools to the game and since this update is essentially known as the copper update you
你肯定猜到了这些新工具的材料
would be right to assume that these new tools are made of,
没错 就是铜
well, copper.
只需准备些铜锭和木棍  就能打造铜剑
Just simply grab yourself some copper ingots and some sticks and you will be able to craft yourself a copper sword,
铜斧 铜镐
a copper axe, a copper pickaxe,
铜铲以及铜锄
a copper shovel and a copper hoe.
我在游戏中对铜的体验就是  挖了一大堆
My personal relation to copper in game is that I mine a bunch of it,
却总忘记它不能制作工具  结果堆在背包里占空间
forget that I can't use it for tools and then hold it in my inventory.
铜矿在游戏中储量丰富  我们想让它发挥更大价值
Copper is really abundant in Minecraft so we wanted to make it more useful to give it more of a purpose.
官方说明铜质工具性能  介于石器和铁器之间
Now these copper tools are described as being better than stone tools but worse than iron tools.
但千万别因此小瞧它们  原因如下
With that said, don't let that put you off using them and here is why.
铜质工具伤害值与石器相同  但耐久度更高
So the copper tools will deal the same amount of damage as stone tools but they have a higher durability.
挖掘破坏方块的速度  也明显快于石器
These copper tools will also work and destroy blocks faster than the stone variants so that will definitely come in
在你尚未获得铁矿  打造铁器之前铜器绝对是得力助手
handy when you haven't come across any iron yet to make iron tools.
根据官方资料站显示
According to the wiki,
铜镐具备开采绿宝石
a copper pickaxe is able to mine and destroy emerald,
与黄金和钻石相关的方块 但在实际游戏中尝试时  这一功能似乎并未生效
gold and diamond related blocks but when we try this in game it doesn't seem to work.
由于铜质工具尚处早期开发阶段
But since these copper tools are in very early development,
未来可能会有所调整
this could change in the future.
我希望这次更新能鼓励更多玩家  真正开采并使用铜矿
I'm hoping that the update will see a lot more people using copper and making sure to mine it and actually put it into tools.
它完美填补了游戏前期空白  让你不必再纠结
It fits really nicely into the early game progression using copper for things you maybe would have before either been
是继续忍受石器低效  还是消耗珍贵铁矿
stuck on stone or had to decide whether you want to use iron for.
另一个值得注意的特性是  铜质工具附魔成功率高于钻石工具
Another interesting thing to note about the new copper tools is that they have a better enchant rate than diamond tools
略低于铁器
but slightly less than iron.
这意味着你可以利用铜器  稳定获取优质附魔效果
So essentially you can use your copper tools to get some pretty good enchantments on them instead of taking the chance
不必担心钻石工具  附魔效果会打折扣
of your diamond tools getting worse enchantments.
而且这些铜质工具的耐久度相当可观
And since these copper tools are going to have pretty good durability,
值得为它们附魔
it might be worth enchanting them.
新版铜器更新不仅带来了铜质工具
Not only did we get copper tools in the new copper update,
我们还迎来了全新护甲类型
we also got a new armour type.
正如你所料  这就是全新的铜质护甲
Now you guessed it, this type of armour is copper armour and it looks like this.
铜质护甲由铜锭打造而成  其合成配方布局与其他类型护甲完全一致
The copper armour is crafted by using copper ingots and it uses the recipe layout as all the other armour counterparts in the game.
这套护甲本身中规中矩
Now the armour itself is okay,
一套完整的铜质护甲  能为玩家提供5点护甲值
I mean a full set of copper armour will give the player 5 chestplate icons on the meter whereas a full set of iron
而全套铁质护甲  则能提供7.5点护甲值
armour gives you 7 and a half.
所以铁质护甲确实还是略胜一筹
So yeah, iron armour is still slightly better.
不过值得注意的是  全套皮革护甲仅能提供3.5点护甲值
It's also worth noting though that a full leather armour set only gives you 3 and a half chestplate icons so yeah,
至少比皮革护甲强多了
at least it's better than leather armour.
还需注意的是  铜甲的耐久度高于皮甲但低于铁甲
It's also useful to know that the copper armour has higher durability than leather armour but less than iron armour so
铜甲虽不算顶尖  但能拥有它还是很酷的
yeah, the copper armour truly is just okay but still cool to have nonetheless.
现在我们要讨论  铜质更新中最令人期待  也最激动人心的功能  那当然就是
Now we are here to talk about the most anticipated and exciting feature of the copper update and that is of course the
铜傀儡与铜质箱子的加入
addition of the copper golem and the copper chest.
铜傀儡最初亮相于2021年Minecraft Live 当时它参与了生物投票与
As some of you know, the copper golem was first announced at Minecraft Live 2021 and it was part of a mob vote between
另外两个候选生物  分别是怒目怪和悦灵
two other mobs which were the glare and the allay.
最终悦灵赢得了生物投票  但Mojang曾明确表示  铜傀儡将在后续版本加入
Now the allay of course won the mob vote but Mojang did say they were going to add the copper golem later on and here we
终于在2025年的今天  Mojang兑现了他们的承诺
are today in 2025 and Mojang have finally delivered.
铜傀儡曾是玩家们的心头好  开发团队也对它情有独钟  我们一直希望能让它以更完美的姿态  重新回归游戏世界
The copper golem was a fan favourite and one beloved in the development team as well and we wanted to bring it back with
更丰富的互动机制  毕竟它可是个超可爱的小家伙
a bit more of an engaging mechanic and also because it's just a cute little thing.
要召唤铜傀儡  你只需要准备普通铜块或涂蜡铜块即可
So in order to get a copper golem you simply just need a regular copper block or a waxed copper block.
然后放个雕刻南瓜在上头  砰的一下就成啦
Then just place a carved pumpkin on top and bam,
铜傀儡便应声而生  同时还会出现一个铜质箱子
you have spawned the copper golem along with a copper chest.
正如你可能知道的
Now as you probably know,
铜会氧化并变色
copper oxidises and changes colour.
这意味着铜傀儡也不例外  会呈现四种不同的氧化形态
This means the copper golem is no exception to the rule and comes in four different colour variants.
这是未氧化的傀儡
These are the unoxidised golem,
这是轻度氧化的傀儡  中度氧化的傀儡  以及完全氧化的傀儡
the exposed golem, the weathered golem and the oxidised golem.
这意味着你可以使用轻度氧化的
This means you can use exposed,
中度氧化和完全氧化的铜块  搭配雕刻南瓜  就能召唤出对应颜色的铜傀儡变体
weathered and oxidised copper blocks along with a carved pumpkin to spawn those colour variants of the copper golem.
铜质箱子的颜色变化规则  与傀儡完全一致  因为召唤傀儡时会同步生成箱子
The same also applies to the copper chest colours as spawning this mob gives you the chest as well.
召唤铜傀儡时还有个有趣玩法  就是能生成双联箱子
Another interesting thing you can do when spawning in the copper golem is to create a double chest.
没错 只需将两个铜块  和两个雕刻南瓜并排放置  就能同时召唤出两个铜傀儡
That's right, just simply place two copper blocks and two carved pumpkins next to each other and you'll get two copper
也会生成一个双联铜箱  正如你所见 而非两个独立箱子
golems but a double copper chest as you can see instead of two single ones.
铜傀儡与铜箱的设计初衷  是为玩家提供更高效的物品管理方案
Now the purpose of the copper golem and the copper chest is to provide the player with much better inventory management.
铜傀儡的核心功能在于  它能从铜箱中分拣物品  并按预设规则进行分类整理
What I mean by this is the copper golem's purpose is to move different items from the copper chest and sort them into
放到它们各自对应的独立箱子中
their own individual chests.
我们对铜傀儡的功能进行了大幅调整
We've changed the copper golem functionality quite a lot.
新机制是它会四处游走  从铜箱中取出物品  并将其放入空箱子中
The new design is that it's going to move around and take items from copper chests and put them in either empty chests
或是放入已有相同物品的箱子  以此协助玩家整理箱内物品
or chests with a matching copy of that item to sort of help clean up your inventory management in your chests.
例如 如果我放入钻石
For example, if I put diamonds,
泥土 面包和橡木木板到铜箱里  铜傀儡就会自动取出钻石堆  放进一个
dirt, bread and oak planks in the copper chest then the copper golem will take the stack of diamonds and put it in one
箱子 接着取出泥土堆  放进另一个箱子
chest but then take the stack of dirt and put it in another chest.
这对于在基地建造储物间  想要自动分类物品的玩家来说  确实非常实用
This is actually really useful if you're creating a storage room in your base and want your items to be sorted
自动分类到不同箱子中
individually and have them organized into different chests.
铜傀儡还有个有趣特性  比如当它想把钻石放进箱子  但箱内
What's also interesting about the copper golem is if they for example want to put diamonds in a chest but it's already
已有泥土  它就会打开箱子
got dirt in it for example then they will open the chest,
发现箱内已有不同物品  便会转身离开  继续寻找其他空箱子
see that it has a different item in it and then walk away from it and find another chest that's either empty or has
或是已有钻石的箱子
diamonds in it as well.
不过 如果铜傀儡一时犯糊涂  你其实可以帮忙把泥土从箱子里取出
You can actually help the copper golem though if they get a bit confused as you can take the dirt out of the chest and
傀儡最终就会如你所愿  将钻石放入那个箱子
then the golem will eventually put the diamonds in said chest as intended.
关于铜傀儡与铜箱的另一个注意事项是
Another thing to note about copper golems and copper chests is that the golem will only take items out of the chest in
每次最多只会取出16个物品
16 stack increments.
所以如果铜箱里有64个钻石  铜傀儡每次只会取出16个
So if you have a 64 stack of diamonds in the copper chest then the golem will only take 16 diamonds out at a time.
新功能的灵感很大程度上来自与社区和创作者的交流
The new functionality comes a lot from talking with the community and talking with creators.
随着我的世界物品不断增多  库存管理变得越来越重要因此能够
Inventory management has become a bigger and bigger thing in Minecraft as more items have been added so being able to
拥有一个能在基地里四处走动  帮你搬运整理物品的小帮手  绝对是个巨大的加分项
have something that goes around and moves things in your base and helps sort of organize things is a big bonus.
既然我们已经探讨了铜傀儡和铜箱的运作机制  现在就来聊聊这两个功能本身
Now that we've talked about the mechanics of the copper golem and copper chest let's talk about these two features
各自的特点
individually.
铜傀儡属于被动型生物  生命值仅有6颗心
So the copper golem is a passive mob and only has six hearts of health.
当玩家击杀铜傀儡时  它死亡后会掉落1到3个铜锭  但你们应该不会这么无情吧
When killed by the player it can drop one to three copper ingots upon death but you guys wouldn't be heartless enough to
忍心对铜傀儡下毒手吧？
end a copper golem would you?
嘿 我是为了拍视频才这么做的  这不算数的好吗
Hey, I had to do it for the purpose of the video it doesn't count okay?
就像铜块一样  铜傀儡本身也会随时间逐渐氧化
Just like the copper blocks the copper golem itself can oxidize over time.
铜傀儡最初会保持未氧化状态  但大约七小时后  它就会开始进入第一阶段的氧化
Okay so as you know the copper golem will start off unoxidized but after around seven hours it will begin the first stage.
第一阶段是“斑驳”状态  这时傀儡会开始褪色  表面逐渐出现绿色斑点
The first stage is the exposed variant where the golem becomes discolored and green spots begin to appear.
随着氧化持续进行  它会变成“风化”状态的铜傀儡  通体呈现绿色并带有褐色斑点
As oxidation continues it becomes a weathered copper golem becoming green in color with brown spots.
随后铜傀儡会进入最终阶段  成为“氧化”状态的铜傀儡  全身布满绿色斑点
Then the copper golem reaches its last stage which is the oxidized copper golem where the mob becomes a teal color with several green spots.
需要注意的是  铜傀儡的氧化阶段不会对其行为产生任何影响
It's worth noting though that the copper golem's oxidation stage will not change the mob's behavior in any way.
现在我们来详细说说铜质箱子
Now let's talk about the copper chest in more detail.
铜质箱子可以通过创造铜傀儡获得  但你也可以用八块铜锭和一个普通箱子来合成
So as you know the copper chest is obtained by creating a copper golem
but you can also craft the chest by using eight copper ingots and one chest.
就像铜块和铜傀儡一样  铜质箱子也会经历完全相同的四个氧化阶段
Just like the copper blocks and copper golem the copper chest is also able to oxidize in the same four stages I
正如我之前提到的
mentioned before.
铜质箱子的储物空间  与普通箱子完全相同  单个铜箱有27个物品栏
The copper chest has the same storage as a regular chest having 27 item slots for a single copper chest and 54 item
双联铜箱则有54个物品栏
slots for a double copper chest.
我忘记提到的另一个铜制品  是铜粒
Another copper item I forgot to mention is the copper nugget.
就像铁粒和金粒一样  现在只需在工作台中摆放铜锭就能将其分解为九个铜粒
Just like iron and gold nuggets copper ingots are now able to be turned into nine copper nuggets by simply placing them in the crafting grid.
铜粒的加入很可能是因为  玩家能够将铁质和金质装备熔炼回收成对应的金属粒
The copper nugget was likely added as players are able to smelt iron and gold equipment in a furnace to give them the
因此同理  铜质装备也应该能通过熔炼获得铜粒
respective nuggets so it makes sense that you should be able to do the same thing with the copper items as well.
Java版铜质更新中新增的下一个功能  就是这些铜质雕像的加入
The next new feature that has been added in the copper update for java edition is the addition of these copper statues
它们看起来是这样的
which look like this.
目前铜质雕像共有八种不同变体
Now there are eight different variants of the copper statue.
这是最基础的普通款
We've got the regular one right here,
这是斑驳的铜傀儡雕像
we've got the exposed copper golem statue,
这是风化的铜傀儡雕像  这是氧化的铜傀儡雕像  以及上蜡后的变体
the weathered one, the oxidized one and then we have the waxed variant.
所以我们还有上蜡的铜傀儡雕像
So we've got the waxed copper golem,
上蜡的斑驳铜傀儡雕像
the waxed exposed copper golem,
上蜡的风化铜傀儡雕像  以及最后这款  上蜡的氧化铜傀儡雕像
the waxed weather copper golem statue and finally the waxed oxidized copper golem statue.
抱歉 但咱们能先吐槽下  这些物品名称有多冗长吗？
I'm sorry can we just talk about how long some of the item names are?
“上蜡的斑驳铜傀儡雕像”  这名字长得简直离谱
I mean waxed exposed copper golem statue that is literally such a mouthful.
这些铜傀儡雕像最酷的地方在于  你可以通过互动来改变它们的姿势
Now what's really cool about these copper golem statues is that you can interact with them to change their poses.
所以右键点击它们时  铜傀儡最多能切换四种姿势  我觉得这些造型真的
So if you right click on them you can have up to four different poses for the copper golem and I think these look really
太帅了 我超爱这些造型
cool, I'm a big fan of these.
铜傀儡的四种姿势分别是  这个坐姿
So the four different poses is the sitting pose right here and then you've got its walking animation pose and then
还有从箱子里取物的姿势  以及最后这个  单纯站立的姿势
you've got the pose of it taking something out of a chest I think it is and then you've got the pose of it just standing still.
要获得这些铜傀儡雕像   你需要等待普通铜傀儡生物
Now in order to obtain one of these copper golem statues you need to wait for a regular copper golem mob to turn into an
氧化一段时间后  这个氧化铜傀儡就会变成雕像
oxidized copper golem and then eventually after some time this oxidized copper golem will turn into a statue.
两小时后
Two hours later.
经过一段时间  这个氧化铜傀儡已经变成了氧化铜雕像
As you can see after some time this oxidized copper golem has turned into a oxidized copper statue and you can now
现在你可以与之互动  随意切换所有姿势 就像这样
interact with it and change all of the poses with it as you can see.
如果你想改变铜傀儡雕像的氧化状态  只需要靠近这个
Now if you want to change the oxidization state of the copper golem statue then all you need to do is go up to this
氧化铜傀儡雕像  用斧头右键点击它 现在它已经变成了斑驳铜质状态
oxidized copper golem statue with an axe and right click on it and as you can see it's now become a weathered copper golem statue.
然后再次右键点击  它就会变成风化铜傀儡  继续点击还能变回普通铜傀儡状态
You can then right click on it again to turn it into an exposed copper golem and then again to turn it into a regular
最后再右键点击一次  就能让它变回普通的铜傀儡生物
copper golem and then you can right click on it a final time to turn it back into a regular copper golem mob.
看 这家伙又活蹦乱跳了  它正悠闲地四处走动  说实话这效果相当酷
So as you can see this guy is alive and well again he's walking around chilling and uh yeah it's actually pretty cool
你可以把它们变回普通的铜傀儡
that you can turn them back into regular copper golems.
即将介绍的  是Java版铜质更新中另一个令人惊喜的新特性
The next new feature that we have been blessed with in the minecraft copper update for java edition is a feature that
这个新特性虽然与铜无关  但同样令人兴奋  那就是书架
has nothing to do with copper but is an exciting one nonetheless and that is the shelves which look like this.
这些书架共有12种木质变体  比如你现在看到的橡木书架
Now the shelves come in 12 different wood variants as you can see we've got the oak shelf,
云杉木书架  白桦木书架
the spruce shelf, the birch shelf,
丛林书架  金合欢书架
the jungle shelf, the acacia shelf,
深色橡木书架  还有红树木书架
the dark oak shelf, we've got the mangrove shelf,
樱花木书架  苍白橡木书架  以及竹制书架
the cherry shelf, the pale oak shelf and we've got the bamboo shelf,
绯红菌书架  最后是诡异菌书架
the crimson shelf and finally the warped shelf.
我为什么要说这些？
Why did I say all of that?
我猜你们早就知道了
I'm sure you guys knew this already,
说这么多真是够累的
it was a lot of stuff to say.
其实没必要逐个列举所有书架  不过嘛...你们懂我意思就行
I probably didn't need to list off all of the shelves individually but uh yeah you guys get the gist.
要在我的世界中制作这些新书架  你需要使用去皮原木材料
Now in order to craft these new shelves in minecraft you are going to need the stripped variants of the wood so if I put
放入6块去皮橡木  就能合成橡木书架 看这里
in 6 stripped oak logs you can see I can craft an oak shelf right here.
放入6块去皮樱花木  就能合成超酷的樱花木书架
Then if I put in 6 stripped cherry logs you can see I can craft a cherry shelf which looks really cool.
最后放入6块去皮苍白橡木  就能得到苍白橡木书架  同样如此
And finally if I put in 6 stripped variants of the pale oak logs you can see that I get a pale oak shelf which again
看起来超酷
looks really cool.
如你所见  每个书架都有3个物品栏位  所以如果我把钻石放进去
Now as you can see the individual shelves have 3 item slots to store items so if I store some diamonds in this shelf
这里放钻石会显示在中间  再放入钻石矿就会出现在左侧
right here you'll see that it appears in the middle and then if I put in some diamond ore it appears on the left and
放入钻石块则会显示在右侧
then if I put in the diamond block it appears on the right.
这些书架还有个超棒的功能  能存放最多64个一组的物品  比如我可以放一整组牛排
What's also cool about the shelves is that you can store items up to a 64 stack so I can put a stack of steaks,
一组鸡肉  和一组羊肉
a stack of chicken and a stack of mutton.
不知道能不能存放这些新的铜傀儡雕像呢？
I wonder if you can store these new copper golem statues?
没错 可以放进去  它们看起来特别滑稽  我们把其他几个也摆上去  搞定
Yep you can, you can put them in there and they look really funny so let's just put the others in there and there you go.
这些展示方式太棒了
I love the way these are displayed.
所以基本上  你可以把任何物品放进这些书架  不得不说它们真的超级实用
So yeah you can pretty much put any item you want in these shelves and I have to say they're going to be really useful
对于既想整理物品又想同时展示的玩家来说  简直是完美选择
for people that want to organize their items as well as display them at the same time.
现在你看到了
But there you have it,
以上就是我的世界铜质更新中  已公布的全部新铜质特性
those are all of the new copper features that have been revealed for the Minecraft Copper Update.
不过官方其实不叫这个名字
It's not actually called that by the way,
我猜既然新增内容都和铜相关  叫它“铜质更新”也挺合理
I just figured since every feature added is copper related it makes sense to call it the Copper Update.
总之 好好享受这些新铜傀儡和铜制宝箱吧
Anyways enjoy the new copper golems and copper chests.
好的 非常感谢观看  更多我的世界铜质更新视频  很快就会上线  那么...再见啦！
But yeah thanks so much for watching and more Minecraft Copper Update videos will be coming real soon and uh yeah goodbye!
在 Youtube 上关注原作者：iDeactivateMC
原标题：700 Things Added in Minecraft Updates (2020 - 2025)
原视频上传日期：2025年7月31日
翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
翻译质量权威评价：原来25年就有小拉即用机翻糊弄人了
♥无偿翻译，用爱发电♥
如果你喜欢这个视频，请多多支持和评论哒~ o((>ω< ))o
字幕制作不易，喜欢的话支持一下我吧！